<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-building-titanic</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1908-04-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=White+Star+line&st=text&r=0.553,0.822,0.335,0.569,0</id>
        <rel>
        1
        <text>
          WHITE STAR LINE TO BUILD
          BIGGEST SHIPS YET PROJECTED
          By Associated Press.
          LIVERPOOL. April Two new
          White Star liners which will be the
          largest vessels yet projected will be
          laid down at Belfast next June. The
          exact measurements of the steamers
          have not been given out/but they will
          be over 840 feet In length, 78 feet in
          breadth and with a gross tonnage of
          45,000, or 50,000.
          The ships are to be fitted with com
          bination turbines and reciprocating
          engines guaranteed to maintain a
          speed of twenty-one knots. The names
          of the vessels are to be Olympic and
          Titanic.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1908-10-02/ed-1/?sp=9&q=White+Star+line&st=text&r=0.319,0.029,0.279,0.474,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          MAMMOTH LINERS LINERSPUZZLE LINERSPUZZLEOFFICIALS
          PUZZLE PUZZLEOFFICIALS PUZZLEOFFICIALSEnglishmen OFFICIALS OFFICIALSEnglishmen
          Englishmen Fear 60000Ton 60000TonBoats 60OOOTonBoats 60f000TonBoats
          Boats Cant Be BeDocked BeDocked BeDocked
          Docked DockedLONDON DockedLONDON DockedLONDON
          LONDON Oct 2 2Brltl British h shipbuilding shipbuildingexperts ebipbulkllngexperts
          shipbuildingexperts
          experts are puzzled to know how the theWhite theWhite theWhite
          White Star officiate will land passen passengers p paseengem s en engers
          gers and cargo fromuthe tront fro tbe a lines two pro prospective protpectie propective
          spective 80000 tonn tonnars the Titanic and andOlympic andhmpfc andt
          Olympic OlympicThe t ilympicThe hmpfcThe
          The Mauretanla and Lusitania of not notmuch notmuch notmuch
          much more than half ha1 the proposed proposedcrafts propo proposedcrafts ed edrafts
          crafts tonnage have no more room roomthan roomtllan roomthan
          than they need to get through the theAmbrose theAmbroee theAmbrose
          Ambrose channel and Into the Mersey Merseynt
          nt tt t Liverpool LiverpoolThe LiverpoolThe LiverpoolThe
          The popular opinion here Is that a avessel afssel avessel
          vessel of 0600 tons would have to todo tod tolo
          do d Its loading and unloading at sea seaMarine 3eLlarlne seaMarine
          Marine statisticians stati tJdans have figured that thatthe thattite
          I
          the t he tonnage of the e entire Spanish ar arnada armada armada
          mada of 129 l ships ships which tried to land landan landn
          an n army In England in Queen Eliza Elizabeths EJlzahetbs Elizabeths
          beths reign was only 50139 50139Considerable 58139Considerable 13 13Considerable
          Considerable progress is being made madewith madewith madewith
          with construction work on the Olym Olympic Olympic Olympie
          pic In Harland Wolffs yard at atBelfast atBElrut atBelfast
          Belfast but the Titanic keel blocks blockswill blockswill l lwill
          will not be laid until January
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1909-01-03/ed-1/?sp=59&q=White+Star+Titanic&r=-0.059,0.277,0.951,0.808,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          A MIGHTY CRADLE FOR GIGANTIC TWINS.
          This aantry cost $\COO,COO. It was erected fop the express purooie of corstructinn the two
          new
          White Star steamships, Olympic and Titanic.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1909-05-30/ed-1/?sp=59&q=White+Star+Titanic&st=text&r=-0.078,0.093,1.05,1.05,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text> TWO XEW GIAXTS OF SEA. The Titanic and the Olympic W3l lie Largest Steamships in
          World. Although what will be the largest two steamships In the world, the Titanic and the
          Olympic, of the White Star Line, are mere skeletons just now in their Lie million-dollar
          double gantry at Belfast, Ireland the marine architects know exactly bow they are going to
          look when they start on their maiden passage to this port. From the plans and
          specifications the designers have made a wush drawing showing bow 'he monsters will look
          when In the water and ready to sail. Although at nrst glance the illustration suggests the
          Isauretania and Lusitania. with their four gigantic funnels, there Is something in the
          appearance of the new levia thans that Is typical of a White Star steamship. The great
          height of the new liners and the broad sweep of the bridge elves some idea of their 80.J80
          tons displacement. The builders have almost elimi nated the old cusr im of carying masts,
          «nd In this respect the targesi ships in the world resemble the Old Dominion steamers, tha
          smallest passenger carrying vessels in the American coastwise service. All the old
          Dominior Mners have only one mast. g the 1 ;i' i Titanic. Thrse tw< vessels are being built simultaneously
            sid* by side In a steel gantry that was begun a
            year before the keels were laid, and which cost
            over a million dollars. The new liners will each
            n«» S» feet long, with 92-foot beam. The unusual
            beam la equivalent to the length of some of the
            fast utenrn yachts of this port. The Olympic and
            Titanic will iw» read] for the New York. South
            ampton an.i Cherbourg *»*r\ im of the White Star
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93063916/1910-01-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=White+Star+Titanic&r=-0.078%2C0.461%2C1.171%2C0.994%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          THE WORLDS LARGEST VESSEL VESSELTHE VESSELTHE ESSEIJTHE
          THE TITANIC NOW NO BEING BUILT
          Here la an architectural picture of the steamship Titanic which Is being beingbuilt
          beingbunt beingbuilt
          built for the White Star line at Belfast also a view of the giant steel cradle cradleiu
          iu which the ship Is being constructed The keel of the steamship Is seen in inthe inthe
          inthe
          the lower photograph The White Star company Is to have two of these theselaviathans
          theselebtthans theseleviathans
          leviathans and they will be In commission early in 1911 Their launching launchingwill
          will UI signalize a most important era in marine achievement for they will be bobyc beby
          beby
          byc byctil by all odds the largest vessels in the world The Titanic and Olympic will
          willench wUlh willeach
          each h be SCO feet f t in length 92 feet beam 45000 tons register and GOOOO tons
          tonsdisplacement tonsdl tonsdlstixccnwnt
          displacement dl Ilem nt These enormous dimensions are best expressed In comparl comparlS
          30115 S The Washington Va hlngton monument is r x55 55 5 feet high and the Metropolitan
          tower towerlit
          lit New Xt York rliy r f ity rises TOO feet Tbe combined tonnage tonnn e of tbe Olympic
          Olympicand OIrJ11pllukl
          and Tlrxink k far fn r exceeds the tonnage ton n e of all It II the vrbs vessels tssl els
          ls engaged pn n ngld tM1 on both bothskies bothkles bothskies
          skies In the hlsi hI Irlt rl conflict of the Spanish armada HfuJ dn Hud nd It Is even more
          In Interesting Inttresrln inttirestinx
          teresting to know ihir t t the Santa Maria was only em I rIt ii 0 feet fi Plat i t Ions
          IOll a and d 233 tons tonsvet tonhtnhn tonelnirien
          htnhn t vet tat nn thl visw yf f 4r1 1 Columbus Journeyed TO th thp new UP world
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1910-07-11/ed-1/?sp=3&q=White+Star+Titanic&r=-0.436%2C-0.129%2C1.386%2C1.176%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text> NEW LINERS SOON 10 BE LAUNCHED Hr Carlisle Says Olympic and Titanic Will Be Handsomest
        Vessels Afloat. LiOMSTER.S OF 45.000 TONS tvrert Says There Is No Reason '•'■■7 They Should
        Not. Be x Ha-^ ec Praise fin Americans. Vs rt r VT ah!*' "Alexander M Car '~*r r*""e^2^
        'Tir'l— Of the big shipbuild-. i r-r Z Harlassd Wolff, at Belfast. r%r^*£T.d probably the
        most prominent |g!Swj) constructor in Great Britain, ar- T^an yesterday en the .Whit* Star
        »T^> r, of the vessels "which grew *F, o^servatioti in the Belfast yards. i-T^ •"s-i-t bssb
        Bf about sixty, and has .**^i-v tie Crsa he represents for forty; **^~~ezzs According c his
        friends he is f: _.."- talks little, but. thinks much. s .rCl crpt-ired —1? yesterday when
        he j^**^v V about the new-, theusand-fect c t2.r eiants that are seen to leave Kr^,;^ Vt
        Belfast -vT~s -=thir.g at all to say." said Mr fejjsie iSraptly. tm not S" c to talk
        S-TsSlps What "have" I com© over- for" W--V2 SStle trip and the salt baths. rcirg right back
        en the Oceanic on VfeSaai jri-ec t-"- e £e2 waase at Belfast was J.. r -«t £5 coed se the
        salt water of the r, J^ r of Vfeew York, Mr Carlisle replied s'-spese S&! But you see I came
        over to 2*iitt2s» at sea: to get the sea air %i tie salt t-stis or. board the Celtic" Cr tie
        tie bay Carlisle clung v^c^v remark that he -would not T ,v ajjsst ships, but he asksd many
        ques .j.,., ibbct tie harbor and the cutters that aX tie Celtic By degress v,«, warmed up 7.
        -_;* cibject o* stear^ship construction, to •rt^zz. he hsi obßd his life, and declared £2*
        Clynplc and Titanic would but* p^serSsenr ark -"--er- they cams here in 3£- ..-tv, -»--rk or
        these big Etfiaisshlps is rilTor. right and day," he "said, -j "wd have the Olympic ready
        for jssciis October Nothing can com t--c with zs.ezz. in si;* and beauty You rZI zit z.
        reflation. In rocm a^d decoratics xtn. tbese -'cssels cc=s to >*e-v York." BiiMd bet PsMio
        Wants. yz- bs^evs *-ii:<*iz.r BBC* iarjre
£-=silps-
-Te. I SJ:- reascr Thy great liners
£oulc zct be Mscstreeted if the travelling
jcil;c is Tilling tc pay for transpertaticn
~ij?e they net aswSeSfiy lather hard to
-t-A »r v PT» retti g 1& pert?"
v. _.. replied>Xr. Carlisle, with ••c r-■"■;'---"r of a. frown. '"With --i *—c~j'^
        rzzszes can s^'ir.^ big liner jj-mrfl ""rtth ease. Quadruple screws are zz rrzzztr advantage
        As long as you izTr ewe big propellers 90s can hand:?- s blr siip. is net a a-uestior of the
        num ber of prrpeilers. bat the depth they are the waxes They must have solid water w •'•ori
        In You know- 1 cannot always -_..- £i:ps as we would like to build r-.err. We ia->-e tc
        b-uild the^n according to *i£ depth cf the harbors they are re enter I ■_-...-.: good ark
        has been done with the ■sr.:r:: Channel at ..this port. You Ancri;ar:s are able people, and
        you can "Ct--arythi^g yoa set your minds upon.- If ysc wsat ships, are will build them '"T>o
        ywa believe in high speed like that cf the Ururetar-ia 1 the Losaftaals "That again is a
        Question for Che travel- Utg pibSc If people. "want to travel fist they rinst expect to- pay
        for travelling ::_r. The Olympic and the Titanic will zzve 2. sp^ed of ti ■cue knots That is
        rzzi iced for large ships. Ycu will rse sc~e rc-sm those vessels The rt^tfcrsoms -'-'111 be
        unusually large, ezsd tier& will te as abundance of room every ■"•isre. Fir example, we win
        have an ex c^zzzliy large room off the. dining Bar tons T-ie-r* people may meet before din-
        Sar bold receptlcns. The decoration? Till be unsurpassed They will be the fr&sr tliit money
        can buy They will not s^rc bs the most magnificent, bui they Tin i« th& most substantial and
        solid that «-ver -J-ere put tote a steamship." If- Carlisle laughed when asked -what isiarii
        cf the big Huropa. which the Hsm lur?-American Lin© had contracted for ti-rtly bifcirp- the
        recent financial panic in Tiev 2.r^ to have s. Sn?> new vessel,"* he f-ii* Kf an
        exceptionally big typ* Hsrr Alt&rt Eallin. of the Hamburg-Am«*rican lise, is 'd. marvellous
        nan He know? the Ft^cnsiir. business He has done big "rlrps, ar.d vQ] continue to fin big
        things. -fe 'Z th© best, ■ad I understand one of Tzzrt profitable and popular, BtaMneb*ns
        "tf~The Hamburg-American L'r:"=- is the -a-hich -i-ec. built several years in cur yards st
        Belfast. Ciyrrcic Launching in the Fa!!. Aricfci when the Olympic and the Titanic "•xeli
        visit tbea»«atan Mr C^rliEl* said. win launch The Olympic in October tzi she should be in
        service in tbe middle r ISCi. The vessels are so large and there t'j much to be done an them
        after the hww^fag that they car.not be sent out be-; f-.-* that time the Titanic will
        probably ft ready MSI three or four months after Olympic sails on her maiden passage "*-'.i6
        is the first vacation Mr Carlisle has h;f in three years. The work at th*- yards its kept
        him there constantly since his rir!t here res years ap» He pointed to t-.'j Brooklyn Bridge
        on the way -up bay remarked that he went across it on th&. strands while it was in ceur?e c!
        ccrstricticn. He expressed great Inter the railroad terminal facilities in this fcty, tnfl
        stewed much praise on the 3c *«ssraLtton and ability of Americans He f *Slss oat .IP Morgan
        as on* of -Assert-. c ?reir men, who invariably did that "^iJcS hf. kd planned to do rz'r*
        raofat than 7(*i,V<^ tons in ccurs*
wtstructtoji at Belfaßt,*" he said, "and
.t Ere -r- unusually busy ICe one
lies ths great amount of work required
bc!ld such big steamships 5? the
zr.i the Olympic. rbere only
European
Visitors
npiran Columns
\i -York Tribune
a reliable £uidc to the best
Ebops, hotels and resorts.
Consult These Columns
Before Sailing
much valuable time will
be "saved for sightseeing.
sea ■"•a- (q r£t 6ve 2 fairt rr3 of it,
that Is for one to visit the yards.
To. Be Things of Bsauty.
too. the average person cannot
understand the tremendous amount of
ac-sey put Into ta« decoration Only an
■TOM or an architect can know the real
fceautv or understand the time and the
money required to make the interior* of
the big ships. Thus far there- I? hardly
anything that caa surpass the decorations
OB the Mauritania Be patient and watch
few the decorations on the. Olympic."
air. Carlisle -was employed at the Eel
35- yards when the first Oceanic of the
hit* Star Line was launched. When the
second Oceanic, now in port, was launched
MS left the -ways under hi? direction.
The Olympic and Titanic -will be 4S<*V
ton vessels. They in called "thcusand
foof ships, but their length win be MO
fee* The new Hamburg: American liner
hot- under construction at Stettin will be
S?6 feet, -with a tonnage of 45. W. The
Msure-tar.ia. and the LuEitania are each
feet in length with a tonnage of 32.500
When it was announced last month in
London that the great docks -would be
constructed en the Mersey the Ctmard
L;?.!, it is said, planned to construct new
liters of 60.060 tons.
      </text>
    </results>

    <result>
      <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1911-05-31/ed-1/?sp=5&q=titanic&r=0.539%2C0.602%2C0.445%2C0.377%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        MONSTEB LINER LAUNCHED.
        Steamer Titanic Slides Into Water
        at Belfast.
        BELFAST, May .11.?Enthusiastic
        crowds lined the banks of the River
        lStar line's great steamer Titanic was
        launched with appropriate ceremonies
        this morning.
        The Titanic will enter the White Star's
        New York-Soutl^ampton service late in
        the year, but her sister vessel Olympic
        steams from Southampton two weeks
        hence for New York, and these two sea
        monsters, each 45,000 tons register,
        882Vt feet long and 92 H fo*t broad,
        boast the distinction of being the
        largest and finest, vessels in the world
        These massive ships are also notable
        for the enchanting beauty and the un
        usual spaciousness of their passenger ac
        commodations, and in first, second and
        third class the greatest comfort is prom
        ised. On both steamers swimming pools,
        tennis and hand ball courts, and Turkish
        and electric bath establishments ars
        among the Innovations introduced for the
        pleasure of the passengers.
      </text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86086633/1912-04-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=titanic&r=0.651%2C0.972%2C0.192%2C0.163%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        TITANIC'S MAIDEN TRIP.
        Sister Ship to the Olympic of White
        Star Line Snls Next Week.
        Lorn! on, April The gigantic new
        st Mam-ship Titanic of thr White Star
        line arrive.) todoy at Setithamptt n
        from the MinN of her bulkiers at H-l-
        fast. She is to be marie re.iriy for herj
        maitlen trip across the Atlantl the
        atnri al ertotch la scheduled for sVed.
        Oaaday af next week. The Titanic is a
        sister ship to the Olympic. 8he Is 0
        leet hmg and has a d b placement of
        r.o 000 tons. The travellmr Ust n the
        bb ship will have coo names "Hi its
        brt lass roll, in addition to 500 BOO
        ot l i lass and third cabin oa
        sengt ts. To this will be adder, the
        n v oi sua makina a t ui tlo.tiiiK
        pojsilatlon of mir1y t.ooe.
      </text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86058226/1912-04-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=titanic+titantic&st=text&r=0.168,0.27,0.749,1.271,0</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        TITANTIC SAILS ON
        HER FIRST VOYAGE
        White Star Liner the Largest
        Vessel that Ever Sailed
        the Seas.
        (National News Association)
        LONDON, April 10. Carrying 1400
        passengers the liner Titanic of the
        White Star line, than which there is
        no larger vessel afloat, sailed from
        Southhampton today on her maiden
        voyage bound for New York. The Tt
        tanic which is of 45,000 tons displace
        ment Is sister ship to the Olympic.
        All the special suites of rooms in
        stituted as an innovation in the Titan
        ic were occupied when the passage be
        gun. These suites consist of bed
        rooms, sitting room, bath room, and
        servant's room and have their own
        private deck promenade isolated from
        the rest of the ship and not overlooked
        by any other passengers.
        The Titanic also possesses another
        new feature in its Louis XVI. restaur
        ant. Her sister ship the Olympic, also
        has this feature but on a smaller
        scale. It proved so popular, however,,
        that the White Star company decided
        to have Jhe one on the Titanic greatly
        enlarged. Adjacent to it is a special
        reception room for the use of passen
        gers taking meals in the restaurant.
        The Titanic while its engineering
        principal is the same as that of the
        Olympic, is expected by experts on
        navigation to make faster time than
        the Olympic because of a slight dif
        ference in the curvature of the propel
        ler blades.
      </text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86074033/1911-02-18/ed-1/?sp=2&q=construction%2C+olympic%2C+ship%2C+titanic%2C+vessel%2C+white+star+line&r=0.238,0.205,0.711,0.603,0</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        ABOUT once In a decade anew
        fleet of ocean liners is launch
        ed, setting anew standard for
        size, luxury and safety at sca
        the great ships which are
        thought to express the last word in
        boat building are suddenly found
        dwarfed by their new sisters and rele
        gated to a second place. The new
        fleet now under construction, in turn,
        surpasses all the great ships which
        have gone before.
        The world has scarcely become ac
        customed to using the Mauretania as
        a synonym for large objects, when
        two great ships, the Olympic and the
        Titanic, were designed to surpass all
        of her dimensions. No sooner was one
        of these liners launched than the own
        ers of'the Mauretania planned anew
        ship of even greater length. Now,
        in turn, comes the greatest of all
        ocean liners, the Europa, which is still
        larger. With the increase in length,
        beafii and tonnage, comes a corre
        sponding development in the luxury
        of equipment. One may no longer
        call the great ocean liners floating ho
        tels, since the new boats offer many
        more attractive and novel features not
        yet attempted by the builder of hotels.
        The new liners have all, even more
        than the comforts of a palatial
        home.
        The supremacy of the seas in black
        and white is as follows:
        Vessel. Length. Tonnage.
        Mauretania 790 ft. 32,500
        Olympic SCO ft. 48,000
        Europa 900 ft. 50,000
        Statistics are likely to be stupid
        things and the mere recital of dimen
        sions, however large, give little idea
        of the overpowering bulk of such a
        ship as the Europa. The new liner
        will have a displacement of about
        70,000 tons. In other words, the ma
        terial used in this construction will
        weigh 140,000,000 pounds. It would,
        therefore, require 1,400,000 men. or
        about the population of Philadelphia,
        each carrying 100 pounds, to handle
        this material. If this material was
        EUROPA
        jeAittxt* ALfOMrr y/rro& A
        TfAUtfL TAW A l
        t'TilC/YLrS'O

        —f —f’-JW
        J)3
        Ship Dimensions Compared.
        loaded upon the largest American
        freight cars. It would fill a train 40
        miles in length, which, by the way,
        would extend all the way across the
        Panama canal. The combined ca
        pacity of the three largest hotels in
        New York city is 3,235 persons, while
        the Europa carries 4,250 passengers.
        Ship With Nine Decks.
        The Europa will have a beam of
        96 feet, so that her deck will be as
        wide as Broadway in New York city
        at its widest point. She will have
        nine decks above the water line, thus
        making her literally a skyscraper
        afloat. The population of a small
        city will be luxuriously accommodated
        aboard without crowding, since her
        capacity will slightly exceed 5,000.
        The old familiar standard of compari
        son. such as the height of the Statue
        of Liberty or the Washington monu
        ment, Is completely outclassed.
        Some idea of the enormous size of
        the Europa may be had from the or
        der which has been given for 2,000,000
        feet of Oregon fir to be used for the
        decks alone. For months this lum
        ber has been lying near Portland,
        Ore., before being shipped to Ger
        many. Special care has been taken
        to provide only clear, vertical grain
        wood, which has been selected with
        the greatest care.
        With the unprecedented amount of
        cabin and deck space available on the
        Europa, a number of unique features
        become possible which have never
        before been attempted on a ship. None
        of the staterooms will be cramped, as
        on the early boats. For those who
        care to travel with all the comforts
        of home, there will be complete suites
        available. There will be a choice of
        dining rooms for those who do not
        care for the main dining salon; there
        will be a Ritz-Carlton restaurant, a
        grill room, tea garden and even a
        rathskeller. Spacious palm gardens,
        which in winter may be converted
        Into sun parlors, will occupy the up
        per deck. Several ladies’ salons fin
        ished In different decorative periods
        will appeal to the tastes of different
        nationalities. All of these salons will
        be connected by telephone to the pri
        vatcabins are perhaps two or three city
        blocks apart may talk with one an
        other.
        The gymnasium on the Europa will
        be much larger and more completely
        equipped than any heretofore install
        ed. In addition to the regular apparat
        us, there will be a running track, so
        that an athlete could actually cross
        the ocean without breaking training.
        The mechanical exercising devices al
        ready introduced on some ships will
        be very complete, enabling one to ex
        ercise any set of muscles without ef
        fort or enjoy a mechanical camel or
        horseback ride. An experienced at
        tendant will be in charge of the gym
        nasium to offer intelligent advice to
        those seeking exercise.
        To Have Many Luxuries.
        A special squash court will be built
        In connection with the gymnasium.
        Nearby will be found a large swim
        ming pool and completely equipped
        Turkish and Roman baths presided
        over by skillful attendants.
        The Europa will be ventilated thor
        oughly by anew system. She has no
        ventilators rising above her decks,
        which is so familiar a feature of ocean
        liners, and her long, unbroken deck
        incidentally gives her a very trim and
        shipshape appearance. Air will be
        forced to the lowermost decks by
        powerful air pumps. Every part ol
        the great ship will thus lie supplied
        with currents of pure air to the prop
        er temperature. This system insures
        pure air and equitable temperature
        throughout the ship.
      </text>
    </result>


    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87076843/1916-02-24/ed-1/?sp=3&q=bicycle</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
      <text></text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86064187/1918-05-04/ed-1/?sp=7&q=bicycle</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
      <text></text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042354/1918-05-08/ed-1/?sp=10&q=bicycle</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
      <text></text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89061521/1942-06-12/ed-1/?sp=4&q=bicycle</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
      <text></text>
    </result>
    <result>

      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89061521/1942-06-12/ed-1/?sp=4&q=bicycle</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
      <text></text>
    </result>

    <id>
      https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064469/1909-12-28/ed-1/?sp=4&q=construction%2C+olympic%2C+ship%2C+titanic%2C+vessel%2C+white+star+line&r=-0.005,0.142,0.714,0.606,0</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>
      BIGGEST OF ALL
      OCEAN LINERS,
      Gigantic S1is to Jo n the At
      lanid, Fleet.
      EACH CARRYING 5,000 PEOPLE
      Olympic and Titanic Will Be 860 Feet
      Long, Seventy Feet Longer Than Any
      Ship Afloat-To Have All the Splen
      dors of a Great Hotel and a Big Salt
      Water Swimming Bath.
      Near: the end of the year 1911 there
      vill cross the Atlantic ocean the great
      est steamship that ever drove past
      ,tandy IIOok 0c its way to New York
      :l vense th!m excuedls by seventy feet
      the length of the giant Cunarders, the
      Lusitania and Mauretania. When these
      great vessels camne out many of those
      who looked at the majestic sisters felt
      sure that in these two the last word in
      marine construction had been reached.
      But the Olympic, now under con
      struction at Belfast. Ireland, for the
      White Star line, exceeds these two in
      size by almost as great a margin as
      the Lusitania and Mauretania exceed
      the older Lucanla and Campania. The
      newer Cunarders are 790 feet in length.
      The length of the White Star giantess
      is 860 feet. The Cunarders have a
      beam of 88 feet; that of the Olympic
      is 92 feet. In displacement the new
      vessel exceeds the older ones by 3,000
      tons. She will not be endowed with
      the high speed of the ocean grey
      hounds.
      Titanic, a sister vessel to the Olym
      pic, is also under construction at Bel
      fast, but the work upon this other
      vessel is not as far advanced as it
      is on the Olympic. Each ship will
      have accommodations for 5,000 pas
      sengers and for a crew of 600.
      Each vessel will have nine steel decks,
      and on the upper of these there will
      be a spacious entrance hall, dining
      saloons, smoking rooms, libraries, wo
      men's parlors or drawing rooms, grill,
      lounge rooms and restaurants as well
      as a main saloon about ninety feet
      wide.
      Skating Rink on Upper Deck.
      One of the upper decks is to be com
      pletely inclosed to serve as a ballroom
      or skating rink. Instead of canvas
      partitions or awnings to keep out the
      wind and rain the whole will be in
      closed with glass windows similar to
      those in railway carriages. By day
      this spacious apartment may be used
      as a sun parlor or promenade, and it
      will be large enough to enable several
      hundred passengers to move about
      with ease and comfort.
      In addition to extended suits of
      rooms complete flats will be available.
      thus making it possible to cross the
      Atlantic In the enjoyment of all the
      privacy of one's own home. Ocean
      going fiats will comprise bedrooms,
      sitting rooms, private bathrooms and
      even a jprivate library. all en suite.
      Cabins with private shower baths at
      tached, a great salt water swimming
      bath large enough to permit of diving
      and a well equipped gymnasium are to
      be among the features which will be
      Introduced.
      Veranda Cafe on Board.
      The main dining saloon will be fur
      nished to seat 600 persons at once,
      and should a guest tire of this grand
      chamber he can wander from one cafe
      to another--each day have his meals
      in a different aparinient. The veranda
      cafe will also be a leading feature of
      these ships. It will be placed on one
      of the upper decks far astern, fully
      fifty feet above the sea level, and as it
      will be constructed with exposed raft
      ers intwined with vines and creeping
      plants and have latticed sides, it will
      make the illusion of a cafe at the sea
      side almost perfect.
      Precautions Again t Danger.
      Each steamer will be divided into
      upward of thirty steel compartments
      separated by heavy bulkheads. An
      automatic device on the bridge will
      control all these heavy steel doors,
      making it possible for a single hand to
      close them all in almost an instant in
      case of danger. Each of these doors
      will be electrically connected with a
      chart on the bridge, where each door
      will be represented by a small electric
      light, and when one of these doors
      closes the light will burn red, but
      while it remains open the disk will be
      quite dark. The officer on the bridge
      will thus be able to see at a glance
      whether or not all the compartments
      have been closed.
      Yet another set of safety devices will
      guard against tire in any portion of
      the vessel. A series of thermostats
      will be scattered throughout the great
      framework, so arranged as to indicate
      a rise in the tempetrature above a cer
      tain point. Should the' temperature
      reach the danger point, the fact will
      be immediately commnunn ated to the
      oilcer on the bridge by the ringing
      of an electric bell, while an electric
      light on a great chart on the wall will
      brP red.
      ,T vessels will be of the triple
      'serw type and are designed for a
      So t 21 knots an hour. Each ship
      I.wl have three propellers, and. like the
      ~Cardsei. will carry four funsels
      pole ventiltatr mmats.
      1wer lintted with wbelass
      es ghuta. auseL
    </text>
    </result>


  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
