<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-building-titanic</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1908-04-23/ed-1/?sp=1&q=White+Star+line&st=text&r=0.553,0.822,0.335,0.569,0</id>
        <rel>
        1
        <text>
          WHITE STAR LINE TO BUILD
          BIGGEST SHIPS YET PROJECTED
          By Associated Press.
          LIVERPOOL. April Two new
          White Star liners which will be the
          largest vessels yet projected will be
          laid down at Belfast next June. The
          exact measurements of the steamers
          have not been given out/but they will
          be over 840 feet In length, 78 feet in
          breadth and with a gross tonnage of
          45,000, or 50,000.
          The ships are to be fitted with com
          bination turbines and reciprocating
          engines guaranteed to maintain a
          speed of twenty-one knots. The names
          of the vessels are to be Olympic and
          Titanic.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1908-10-02/ed-1/?sp=9&q=White+Star+line&st=text&r=0.319,0.029,0.279,0.474,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          MAMMOTH LINERS LINERSPUZZLE LINERSPUZZLEOFFICIALS
          PUZZLE PUZZLEOFFICIALS PUZZLEOFFICIALSEnglishmen OFFICIALS OFFICIALSEnglishmen
          Englishmen Fear 60000Ton 60000TonBoats 60OOOTonBoats 60f000TonBoats
          Boats Cant Be BeDocked BeDocked BeDocked
          Docked DockedLONDON DockedLONDON DockedLONDON
          LONDON Oct 2 2Brltl British h shipbuilding shipbuildingexperts ebipbulkllngexperts
          shipbuildingexperts
          experts are puzzled to know how the theWhite theWhite theWhite
          White Star officiate will land passen passengers p paseengem s en engers
          gers and cargo fromuthe tront fro tbe a lines two pro prospective protpectie propective
          spective 80000 tonn tonnars the Titanic and andOlympic andhmpfc andt
          Olympic OlympicThe t ilympicThe hmpfcThe
          The Mauretanla and Lusitania of not notmuch notmuch notmuch
          much more than half ha1 the proposed proposedcrafts propo proposedcrafts ed edrafts
          crafts tonnage have no more room roomthan roomtllan roomthan
          than they need to get through the theAmbrose theAmbroee theAmbrose
          Ambrose channel and Into the Mersey Merseynt
          nt tt t Liverpool LiverpoolThe LiverpoolThe LiverpoolThe
          The popular opinion here Is that a avessel afssel avessel
          vessel of 0600 tons would have to todo tod tolo
          do d Its loading and unloading at sea seaMarine 3eLlarlne seaMarine
          Marine statisticians stati tJdans have figured that thatthe thattite
          I
          the t he tonnage of the e entire Spanish ar arnada armada armada
          mada of 129 l ships ships which tried to land landan landn
          an n army In England in Queen Eliza Elizabeths EJlzahetbs Elizabeths
          beths reign was only 50139 50139Considerable 58139Considerable 13 13Considerable
          Considerable progress is being made madewith madewith madewith
          with construction work on the Olym Olympic Olympic Olympie
          pic In Harland Wolffs yard at atBelfast atBElrut atBelfast
          Belfast but the Titanic keel blocks blockswill blockswill l lwill
          will not be laid until January
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1909-01-03/ed-1/?sp=59&q=White+Star+Titanic&r=-0.059,0.277,0.951,0.808,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          A MIGHTY CRADLE FOR GIGANTIC TWINS.
          This aantry cost $\COO,COO. It was erected fop the express purooie of corstructinn the two
          new
          White Star steamships, Olympic and Titanic.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1909-05-30/ed-1/?sp=59&q=White+Star+Titanic&st=text&r=-0.078,0.093,1.05,1.05,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text> TWO XEW GIAXTS OF SEA. The Titanic and the Olympic W3l lie Largest Steamships in
          World. Although what will be the largest two steamships In the world, the Titanic and the
          Olympic, of the White Star Line, are mere skeletons just now in their Lie million-dollar
          double gantry at Belfast, Ireland the marine architects know exactly bow they are going to
          look when they start on their maiden passage to this port. From the plans and
          specifications the designers have made a wush drawing showing bow 'he monsters will look
          when In the water and ready to sail. Although at nrst glance the illustration suggests the
          Isauretania and Lusitania. with their four gigantic funnels, there Is something in the
          appearance of the new levia thans that Is typical of a White Star steamship. The great
          height of the new liners and the broad sweep of the bridge elves some idea of their 80.J80
          tons displacement. The builders have almost elimi nated the old cusr im of carying masts,
          «nd In this respect the targesi ships in the world resemble the Old Dominion steamers, tha
          smallest passenger carrying vessels in the American coastwise service. All the old
          Dominior Mners have only one mast. g the 1 ;i' i Titanic. Thrse tw< vessels are being built simultaneously
            sid* by side In a steel gantry that was begun a
            year before the keels were laid, and which cost
            over a million dollars. The new liners will each
            n«» S» feet long, with 92-foot beam. The unusual
            beam la equivalent to the length of some of the
            fast utenrn yachts of this port. The Olympic and
            Titanic will iw» read] for the New York. South
            ampton an.i Cherbourg *»*r\ im of the White Star
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn93063916/1910-01-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=White+Star+Titanic&r=-0.078%2C0.461%2C1.171%2C0.994%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          THE WORLDS LARGEST VESSEL VESSELTHE VESSELTHE ESSEIJTHE
          THE TITANIC NOW NO BEING BUILT
          Here la an architectural picture of the steamship Titanic which Is being beingbuilt
          beingbunt beingbuilt
          built for the White Star line at Belfast also a view of the giant steel cradle cradleiu
          iu which the ship Is being constructed The keel of the steamship Is seen in inthe inthe
          inthe
          the lower photograph The White Star company Is to have two of these theselaviathans
          theselebtthans theseleviathans
          leviathans and they will be In commission early in 1911 Their launching launchingwill
          will UI signalize a most important era in marine achievement for they will be bobyc beby
          beby
          byc byctil by all odds the largest vessels in the world The Titanic and Olympic will
          willench wUlh willeach
          each h be SCO feet f t in length 92 feet beam 45000 tons register and GOOOO tons
          tonsdisplacement tonsdl tonsdlstixccnwnt
          displacement dl Ilem nt These enormous dimensions are best expressed In comparl comparlS
          30115 S The Washington Va hlngton monument is r x55 55 5 feet high and the Metropolitan
          tower towerlit
          lit New Xt York rliy r f ity rises TOO feet Tbe combined tonnage tonnn e of tbe Olympic
          Olympicand OIrJ11pllukl
          and Tlrxink k far fn r exceeds the tonnage ton n e of all It II the vrbs vessels tssl els
          ls engaged pn n ngld tM1 on both bothskies bothkles bothskies
          skies In the hlsi hI Irlt rl conflict of the Spanish armada HfuJ dn Hud nd It Is even more
          In Interesting Inttresrln inttirestinx
          teresting to know ihir t t the Santa Maria was only em I rIt ii 0 feet fi Plat i t Ions
          IOll a and d 233 tons tonsvet tonhtnhn tonelnirien
          htnhn t vet tat nn thl visw yf f 4r1 1 Columbus Journeyed TO th thp new UP world
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1910-07-11/ed-1/?sp=3&q=White+Star+Titanic&r=-0.436%2C-0.129%2C1.386%2C1.176%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text> NEW LINERS SOON 10 BE LAUNCHED Hr Carlisle Says Olympic and Titanic Will Be Handsomest
        Vessels Afloat. LiOMSTER.S OF 45.000 TONS tvrert Says There Is No Reason '•'■■7 They Should
        Not. Be x Ha-^ ec Praise fin Americans. Vs rt r VT ah!*' "Alexander M Car '~*r r*""e^2^
        'Tir'l— Of the big shipbuild-. i r-r Z Harlassd Wolff, at Belfast. r%r^*£T.d probably the
        most prominent |g!Swj) constructor in Great Britain, ar- T^an yesterday en the .Whit* Star
        »T^> r, of the vessels "which grew *F, o^servatioti in the Belfast yards. i-T^ •"s-i-t bssb
        Bf about sixty, and has .**^i-v tie Crsa he represents for forty; **^~~ezzs According c his
        friends he is f: _.."- talks little, but. thinks much. s .rCl crpt-ired —1? yesterday when
        he j^**^v V about the new-, theusand-fect c t2.r eiants that are seen to leave Kr^,;^ Vt
        Belfast -vT~s -=thir.g at all to say." said Mr fejjsie iSraptly. tm not S" c to talk
        S-TsSlps What "have" I com© over- for" W--V2 SStle trip and the salt baths. rcirg right back
        en the Oceanic on VfeSaai jri-ec t-"- e £e2 waase at Belfast was J.. r -«t £5 coed se the
        salt water of the r, J^ r of Vfeew York, Mr Carlisle replied s'-spese S&! But you see I came
        over to 2*iitt2s» at sea: to get the sea air %i tie salt t-stis or. board the Celtic" Cr tie
        tie bay Carlisle clung v^c^v remark that he -would not T ,v ajjsst ships, but he asksd many
        ques .j.,., ibbct tie harbor and the cutters that aX tie Celtic By degress v,«, warmed up 7.
        -_;* cibject o* stear^ship construction, to •rt^zz. he hsi obßd his life, and declared £2*
        Clynplc and Titanic would but* p^serSsenr ark -"--er- they cams here in 3£- ..-tv, -»--rk or
        these big Etfiaisshlps is rilTor. right and day," he "said, -j "wd have the Olympic ready
        for jssciis October Nothing can com t--c with zs.ezz. in si;* and beauty You rZI zit z.
        reflation. In rocm a^d decoratics xtn. tbese -'cssels cc=s to >*e-v York." BiiMd bet PsMio
        Wants. yz- bs^evs *-ii:<*iz.r BBC* iarjre
£-=silps-
-Te. I SJ:- reascr Thy great liners
£oulc zct be Mscstreeted if the travelling
jcil;c is Tilling tc pay for transpertaticn
~ij?e they net aswSeSfiy lather hard to
-t-A »r v PT» retti g 1& pert?"
v. _.. replied>Xr. Carlisle, with ••c r-■"■;'---"r of a. frown. '"With --i *—c~j'^
        rzzszes can s^'ir.^ big liner jj-mrfl ""rtth ease. Quadruple screws are zz rrzzztr advantage
        As long as you izTr ewe big propellers 90s can hand:?- s blr siip. is net a a-uestior of the
        num ber of prrpeilers. bat the depth they are the waxes They must have solid water w •'•ori
        In You know- 1 cannot always -_..- £i:ps as we would like to build r-.err. We ia->-e tc
        b-uild the^n according to *i£ depth cf the harbors they are re enter I ■_-...-.: good ark
        has been done with the ■sr.:r:: Channel at ..this port. You Ancri;ar:s are able people, and
        you can "Ct--arythi^g yoa set your minds upon.- If ysc wsat ships, are will build them '"T>o
        ywa believe in high speed like that cf the Ururetar-ia 1 the Losaftaals "That again is a
        Question for Che travel- Utg pibSc If people. "want to travel fist they rinst expect to- pay
        for travelling ::_r. The Olympic and the Titanic will zzve 2. sp^ed of ti ■cue knots That is
        rzzi iced for large ships. Ycu will rse sc~e rc-sm those vessels The rt^tfcrsoms -'-'111 be
        unusually large, ezsd tier& will te as abundance of room every ■"•isre. Fir example, we win
        have an ex c^zzzliy large room off the. dining Bar tons T-ie-r* people may meet before din-
        Sar bold receptlcns. The decoration? Till be unsurpassed They will be the fr&sr tliit money
        can buy They will not s^rc bs the most magnificent, bui they Tin i« th& most substantial and
        solid that «-ver -J-ere put tote a steamship." If- Carlisle laughed when asked -what isiarii
        cf the big Huropa. which the Hsm lur?-American Lin© had contracted for ti-rtly bifcirp- the
        recent financial panic in Tiev 2.r^ to have s. Sn?> new vessel,"* he f-ii* Kf an
        exceptionally big typ* Hsrr Alt&rt Eallin. of the Hamburg-Am«*rican lise, is 'd. marvellous
        nan He know? the Ft^cnsiir. business He has done big "rlrps, ar.d vQ] continue to fin big
        things. -fe 'Z th© best, ■ad I understand one of Tzzrt profitable and popular, BtaMneb*ns
        "tf~The Hamburg-American L'r:"=- is the -a-hich -i-ec. built several years in cur yards st
        Belfast. Ciyrrcic Launching in the Fa!!. Aricfci when the Olympic and the Titanic "•xeli
        visit tbea»«atan Mr C^rliEl* said. win launch The Olympic in October tzi she should be in
        service in tbe middle r ISCi. The vessels are so large and there t'j much to be done an them
        after the hww^fag that they car.not be sent out be-; f-.-* that time the Titanic will
        probably ft ready MSI three or four months after Olympic sails on her maiden passage "*-'.i6
        is the first vacation Mr Carlisle has h;f in three years. The work at th*- yards its kept
        him there constantly since his rir!t here res years ap» He pointed to t-.'j Brooklyn Bridge
        on the way -up bay remarked that he went across it on th&. strands while it was in ceur?e c!
        ccrstricticn. He expressed great Inter the railroad terminal facilities in this fcty, tnfl
        stewed much praise on the 3c *«ssraLtton and ability of Americans He f *Slss oat .IP Morgan
        as on* of -Assert-. c ?reir men, who invariably did that "^iJcS hf. kd planned to do rz'r*
        raofat than 7(*i,V<^ tons in ccurs*
wtstructtoji at Belfaßt,*" he said, "and
.t Ere -r- unusually busy ICe one
lies ths great amount of work required
bc!ld such big steamships 5? the
zr.i the Olympic. rbere only
European
Visitors
npiran Columns
\i -York Tribune
a reliable £uidc to the best
Ebops, hotels and resorts.
Consult These Columns
Before Sailing
much valuable time will
be "saved for sightseeing.
sea ■"•a- (q r£t 6ve 2 fairt rr3 of it,
that Is for one to visit the yards.
To. Be Things of Bsauty.
too. the average person cannot
understand the tremendous amount of
ac-sey put Into ta« decoration Only an
■TOM or an architect can know the real
fceautv or understand the time and the
money required to make the interior* of
the big ships. Thus far there- I? hardly
anything that caa surpass the decorations
OB the Mauritania Be patient and watch
few the decorations on the. Olympic."
air. Carlisle -was employed at the Eel
35- yards when the first Oceanic of the
hit* Star Line was launched. When the
second Oceanic, now in port, was launched
MS left the -ways under hi? direction.
The Olympic and Titanic -will be 4S<*V
ton vessels. They in called "thcusand
foof ships, but their length win be MO
fee* The new Hamburg: American liner
hot- under construction at Stettin will be
S?6 feet, -with a tonnage of 45. W. The
Msure-tar.ia. and the LuEitania are each
feet in length with a tonnage of 32.500
When it was announced last month in
London that the great docks -would be
constructed en the Mersey the Ctmard
L;?.!, it is said, planned to construct new
liters of 60.060 tons.
      </text>
    </results>

    <result>
      <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1911-05-31/ed-1/?sp=5&q=titanic&r=0.539%2C0.602%2C0.445%2C0.377%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        MONSTEB LINER LAUNCHED.
        Steamer Titanic Slides Into Water
        at Belfast.
        BELFAST, May .11.?Enthusiastic
        crowds lined the banks of the River
        lStar line's great steamer Titanic was
        launched with appropriate ceremonies
        this morning.
        The Titanic will enter the White Star's
        New York-Soutl^ampton service late in
        the year, but her sister vessel Olympic
        steams from Southampton two weeks
        hence for New York, and these two sea
        monsters, each 45,000 tons register,
        882Vt feet long and 92 H fo*t broad,
        boast the distinction of being the
        largest and finest, vessels in the world
        These massive ships are also notable
        for the enchanting beauty and the un
        usual spaciousness of their passenger ac
        commodations, and in first, second and
        third class the greatest comfort is prom
        ised. On both steamers swimming pools,
        tennis and hand ball courts, and Turkish
        and electric bath establishments ars
        among the Innovations introduced for the
        pleasure of the passengers.
      </text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86086633/1912-04-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=titanic&r=0.651%2C0.972%2C0.192%2C0.163%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        TITANIC'S MAIDEN TRIP.
        Sister Ship to the Olympic of White
        Star Line Snls Next Week.
        Lorn! on, April The gigantic new
        st Mam-ship Titanic of thr White Star
        line arrive.) todoy at Setithamptt n
        from the MinN of her bulkiers at H-l-
        fast. She is to be marie re.iriy for herj
        maitlen trip across the Atlantl the
        atnri al ertotch la scheduled for sVed.
        Oaaday af next week. The Titanic is a
        sister ship to the Olympic. 8he Is 0
        leet hmg and has a d b placement of
        r.o 000 tons. The travellmr Ust n the
        bb ship will have coo names "Hi its
        brt lass roll, in addition to 500 BOO
        ot l i lass and third cabin oa
        sengt ts. To this will be adder, the
        n v oi sua makina a t ui tlo.tiiiK
        pojsilatlon of mir1y t.ooe.
      </text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86058226/1912-04-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=titanic+titantic&st=text&r=0.168,0.27,0.749,1.271,0</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        TITANTIC SAILS ON
        HER FIRST VOYAGE
        White Star Liner the Largest
        Vessel that Ever Sailed
        the Seas.
        (National News Association)
        LONDON, April 10. Carrying 1400
        passengers the liner Titanic of the
        White Star line, than which there is
        no larger vessel afloat, sailed from
        Southhampton today on her maiden
        voyage bound for New York. The Tt
        tanic which is of 45,000 tons displace
        ment Is sister ship to the Olympic.
        All the special suites of rooms in
        stituted as an innovation in the Titan
        ic were occupied when the passage be
        gun. These suites consist of bed
        rooms, sitting room, bath room, and
        servant's room and have their own
        private deck promenade isolated from
        the rest of the ship and not overlooked
        by any other passengers.
        The Titanic also possesses another
        new feature in its Louis XVI. restaur
        ant. Her sister ship the Olympic, also
        has this feature but on a smaller
        scale. It proved so popular, however,,
        that the White Star company decided
        to have Jhe one on the Titanic greatly
        enlarged. Adjacent to it is a special
        reception room for the use of passen
        gers taking meals in the restaurant.
        The Titanic while its engineering
        principal is the same as that of the
        Olympic, is expected by experts on
        navigation to make faster time than
        the Olympic because of a slight dif
        ference in the curvature of the propel
        ler blades.
      </text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>
        https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86074033/1911-02-18/ed-1/?sp=2&q=construction%2C+olympic%2C+ship%2C+titanic%2C+vessel%2C+white+star+line&r=0.238,0.205,0.711,0.603,0</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        ABOUT once In a decade anew
        fleet of ocean liners is launch
        ed, setting anew standard for
        size, luxury and safety at sca
        the great ships which are
        thought to express the last word in
        boat building are suddenly found
        dwarfed by their new sisters and rele
        gated to a second place. The new
        fleet now under construction, in turn,
        surpasses all the great ships which
        have gone before.
        The world has scarcely become ac
        customed to using the Mauretania as
        a synonym for large objects, when
        two great ships, the Olympic and the
        Titanic, were designed to surpass all
        of her dimensions. No sooner was one
        of these liners launched than the own
        ers of'the Mauretania planned anew
        ship of even greater length. Now,
        in turn, comes the greatest of all
        ocean liners, the Europa, which is still
        larger. With the increase in length,
        beafii and tonnage, comes a corre
        sponding development in the luxury
        of equipment. One may no longer
        call the great ocean liners floating ho
        tels, since the new boats offer many
        more attractive and novel features not
        yet attempted by the builder of hotels.
        The new liners have all, even more
        than the comforts of a palatial
        home.
        The supremacy of the seas in black
        and white is as follows:
        Vessel. Length. Tonnage.
        Mauretania 790 ft. 32,500
        Olympic SCO ft. 48,000
        Europa 900 ft. 50,000
        Statistics are likely to be stupid
        things and the mere recital of dimen
        sions, however large, give little idea
        of the overpowering bulk of such a
        ship as the Europa. The new liner
        will have a displacement of about
        70,000 tons. In other words, the ma
        terial used in this construction will
        weigh 140,000,000 pounds. It would,
        therefore, require 1,400,000 men. or
        about the population of Philadelphia,
        each carrying 100 pounds, to handle
        this material. If this material was
        EUROPA
        jeAittxt* ALfOMrr y/rro& A
        TfAUtfL TAW A l
        t'TilC/YLrS'O

        —f —f’-JW
        J)3
        Ship Dimensions Compared.
        loaded upon the largest American
        freight cars. It would fill a train 40
        miles in length, which, by the way,
        would extend all the way across the
        Panama canal. The combined ca
        pacity of the three largest hotels in
        New York city is 3,235 persons, while
        the Europa carries 4,250 passengers.
        Ship With Nine Decks.
        The Europa will have a beam of
        96 feet, so that her deck will be as
        wide as Broadway in New York city
        at its widest point. She will have
        nine decks above the water line, thus
        making her literally a skyscraper
        afloat. The population of a small
        city will be luxuriously accommodated
        aboard without crowding, since her
        capacity will slightly exceed 5,000.
        The old familiar standard of compari
        son. such as the height of the Statue
        of Liberty or the Washington monu
        ment, Is completely outclassed.
        Some idea of the enormous size of
        the Europa may be had from the or
        der which has been given for 2,000,000
        feet of Oregon fir to be used for the
        decks alone. For months this lum
        ber has been lying near Portland,
        Ore., before being shipped to Ger
        many. Special care has been taken
        to provide only clear, vertical grain
        wood, which has been selected with
        the greatest care.
        With the unprecedented amount of
        cabin and deck space available on the
        Europa, a number of unique features
        become possible which have never
        before been attempted on a ship. None
        of the staterooms will be cramped, as
        on the early boats. For those who
        care to travel with all the comforts
        of home, there will be complete suites
        available. There will be a choice of
        dining rooms for those who do not
        care for the main dining salon; there
        will be a Ritz-Carlton restaurant, a
        grill room, tea garden and even a
        rathskeller. Spacious palm gardens,
        which in winter may be converted
        Into sun parlors, will occupy the up
        per deck. Several ladies’ salons fin
        ished In different decorative periods
        will appeal to the tastes of different
        nationalities. All of these salons will
        be connected by telephone to the pri
        vatcabins are perhaps two or three city
        blocks apart may talk with one an
        other.
        The gymnasium on the Europa will
        be much larger and more completely
        equipped than any heretofore install
        ed. In addition to the regular apparat
        us, there will be a running track, so
        that an athlete could actually cross
        the ocean without breaking training.
        The mechanical exercising devices al
        ready introduced on some ships will
        be very complete, enabling one to ex
        ercise any set of muscles without ef
        fort or enjoy a mechanical camel or
        horseback ride. An experienced at
        tendant will be in charge of the gym
        nasium to offer intelligent advice to
        those seeking exercise.
        To Have Many Luxuries.
        A special squash court will be built
        In connection with the gymnasium.
        Nearby will be found a large swim
        ming pool and completely equipped
        Turkish and Roman baths presided
        over by skillful attendants.
        The Europa will be ventilated thor
        oughly by anew system. She has no
        ventilators rising above her decks,
        which is so familiar a feature of ocean
        liners, and her long, unbroken deck
        incidentally gives her a very trim and
        shipshape appearance. Air will be
        forced to the lowermost decks by
        powerful air pumps. Every part ol
        the great ship will thus lie supplied
        with currents of pure air to the prop
        er temperature. This system insures
        pure air and equitable temperature
        throughout the ship.
      </text>
    </result>


    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87076843/1916-02-24/ed-1/?sp=3&q=bicycle</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
      <text></text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86064187/1918-05-04/ed-1/?sp=7&q=bicycle</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
      <text></text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042354/1918-05-08/ed-1/?sp=10&q=bicycle</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
      <text></text>
    </result>

    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89061521/1942-06-12/ed-1/?sp=4&q=bicycle</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
      <text></text>
    </result>
    <result>

      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89061521/1942-06-12/ed-1/?sp=4&q=bicycle</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
      <text></text>
    </result>

    <id>
      https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064469/1909-12-28/ed-1/?sp=4&q=construction%2C+olympic%2C+ship%2C+titanic%2C+vessel%2C+white+star+line&r=-0.005,0.142,0.714,0.606,0</id>
    <rel>1</rel>
    <text>
      BIGGEST OF ALL
      OCEAN LINERS,
      Gigantic S1is to Jo n the At
      lanid, Fleet.
      EACH CARRYING 5,000 PEOPLE
      Olympic and Titanic Will Be 860 Feet
      Long, Seventy Feet Longer Than Any
      Ship Afloat-To Have All the Splen
      dors of a Great Hotel and a Big Salt
      Water Swimming Bath.
      Near: the end of the year 1911 there
      vill cross the Atlantic ocean the great
      est steamship that ever drove past
      ,tandy IIOok 0c its way to New York
      :l vense th!m excuedls by seventy feet
      the length of the giant Cunarders, the
      Lusitania and Mauretania. When these
      great vessels camne out many of those
      who looked at the majestic sisters felt
      sure that in these two the last word in
      marine construction had been reached.
      But the Olympic, now under con
      struction at Belfast. Ireland, for the
      White Star line, exceeds these two in
      size by almost as great a margin as
      the Lusitania and Mauretania exceed
      the older Lucanla and Campania. The
      newer Cunarders are 790 feet in length.
      The length of the White Star giantess
      is 860 feet. The Cunarders have a
      beam of 88 feet; that of the Olympic
      is 92 feet. In displacement the new
      vessel exceeds the older ones by 3,000
      tons. She will not be endowed with
      the high speed of the ocean grey
      hounds.
      Titanic, a sister vessel to the Olym
      pic, is also under construction at Bel
      fast, but the work upon this other
      vessel is not as far advanced as it
      is on the Olympic. Each ship will
      have accommodations for 5,000 pas
      sengers and for a crew of 600.
      Each vessel will have nine steel decks,
      and on the upper of these there will
      be a spacious entrance hall, dining
      saloons, smoking rooms, libraries, wo
      men's parlors or drawing rooms, grill,
      lounge rooms and restaurants as well
      as a main saloon about ninety feet
      wide.
      Skating Rink on Upper Deck.
      One of the upper decks is to be com
      pletely inclosed to serve as a ballroom
      or skating rink. Instead of canvas
      partitions or awnings to keep out the
      wind and rain the whole will be in
      closed with glass windows similar to
      those in railway carriages. By day
      this spacious apartment may be used
      as a sun parlor or promenade, and it
      will be large enough to enable several
      hundred passengers to move about
      with ease and comfort.
      In addition to extended suits of
      rooms complete flats will be available.
      thus making it possible to cross the
      Atlantic In the enjoyment of all the
      privacy of one's own home. Ocean
      going fiats will comprise bedrooms,
      sitting rooms, private bathrooms and
      even a jprivate library. all en suite.
      Cabins with private shower baths at
      tached, a great salt water swimming
      bath large enough to permit of diving
      and a well equipped gymnasium are to
      be among the features which will be
      Introduced.
      Veranda Cafe on Board.
      The main dining saloon will be fur
      nished to seat 600 persons at once,
      and should a guest tire of this grand
      chamber he can wander from one cafe
      to another--each day have his meals
      in a different aparinient. The veranda
      cafe will also be a leading feature of
      these ships. It will be placed on one
      of the upper decks far astern, fully
      fifty feet above the sea level, and as it
      will be constructed with exposed raft
      ers intwined with vines and creeping
      plants and have latticed sides, it will
      make the illusion of a cafe at the sea
      side almost perfect.
      Precautions Again t Danger.
      Each steamer will be divided into
      upward of thirty steel compartments
      separated by heavy bulkheads. An
      automatic device on the bridge will
      control all these heavy steel doors,
      making it possible for a single hand to
      close them all in almost an instant in
      case of danger. Each of these doors
      will be electrically connected with a
      chart on the bridge, where each door
      will be represented by a small electric
      light, and when one of these doors
      closes the light will burn red, but
      while it remains open the disk will be
      quite dark. The officer on the bridge
      will thus be able to see at a glance
      whether or not all the compartments
      have been closed.
      Yet another set of safety devices will
      guard against tire in any portion of
      the vessel. A series of thermostats
      will be scattered throughout the great
      framework, so arranged as to indicate
      a rise in the tempetrature above a cer
      tain point. Should the' temperature
      reach the danger point, the fact will
      be immediately commnunn ated to the
      oilcer on the bridge by the ringing
      of an electric bell, while an electric
      light on a great chart on the wall will
      brP red.
      ,T vessels will be of the triple
      'serw type and are designed for a
      So t 21 knots an hour. Each ship
      I.wl have three propellers, and. like the
      ~Cardsei. will carry four funsels
      pole ventiltatr mmats.
      1wer lintted with wbelass
      es ghuta. auseL
    </text>
    </result>


  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-badminton</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1886-04-04/ed-1/?sp=12&q=badminton&st=text&r=0.054,-0.118,1.111,1.886,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text> How the Young People of New York ltclux Strict Formality at Badminton* The Way in
          Which n Howlinjj swell Getsilimsell Ip for the Ilariu less Game. New York Letter: 1 have
          read a heap within a month in the society columns ot our city dailies and weeklies, as
          well as in out-of-town letters, concerning one Noa Don. who seems to be accepted as the
          spring-tide belle of Fifth avenue. Non sense! This is too big a town, and even the limits
          of the most pretentious society are too spacious, to permit any single girl to pet
          unquestioned supremacy. I have seen this precious creature, moreover, and 1 am telling you
          Cor keeps that she is no such thing as the accounts make her out. I'm not denying her all
          the wit at repartee to iredited to her. She truly has touguc as iliarp and quick as ever 1
          heard: but what I am impressing on you this minute- is that a Queen of Swelldom, if we
          ever do crown one. will be perfection as to dress. Now. Noa Don is merely a traveled and
          educated gill, who has been round the world to pick up conceits that startle and amuse us;
          who has come into New York with family connections that give her en trance to the charmed
          circles of wealth, and «he makes her witty comments— as nave been so extensively reported
          with considerable cleverness; but when 1 have described her as she presented herself at
          the Academy of Music the other evening yon will understand why I won't concede that she
          ought to be elevated into public view as supremely fine. She ought to huve been arrayed in
          fashionable evening costume, of course, because she sat in a box along with women so
          dressed. But she ap parently aimed to be DISTISCTIVKLY ODD. Her hair was loose and fluffy,
          and the only ornamentation or attempt at coiifure was a curious Bori of gilded thing not
          un like a crown -set on the top of her head. Her dress was pale amber >atm, and its cut
          was not unlike that of the current morning gown. Her anus wene completely covered by
          sleeves and gloves, but her nmiapn was law 111 a Bquariah shape, outlined by a Btand-up
          frill of lace, as little in the fashion cf Queen Elizabeth. No. no; Noa Don can not be
          officially admired, no matter how smart her sayings, until she robes her self in
          accordance with strict fashiou's rules. What a jolly row Miss Cleveland has been kicking
          up. by the way. about low corsages. Still, she is awfully right in con demning some of the
          nudity, and you will remember that 1 have been doing the same missionary sort of work for
          several seasons. i*he makes n special point of it that the line of bareness shall bo high
          enough bo cover all of the dis tinct feminity. He* Idea is that bare amis, an. l so much
          Of the breast as happens to be flat, are not an immodest exposure: but as I looked up from
          the perusal of her letter— it was just before Starting tor B recent ion. and a bevy of
          tirls were randy to go— and my eyes fell on a maiden of exceeding meager nests in
          curvatures, I said to myself: '•Where would the line be dra*vn across that creature if it
          were lowered in obedience to .Miss Cleveland's proposition?'' BOUBKHOLO AIM l( I.LS are so
          frequently asked about by a*ycor respondents that I here give, by general way of answer, a
          number of points. Pil low-shams arc used in preference to fancy trimmed slip overs. Lace
          curtains never go out of fashion. They I.re used for parlors, reception and dlning-rooma,
          bedrooms, and. in fact, for all the rooms of a houso. if preferred to the many novelties
          in what is called .Madras lace. really a muslin brocbe curtain, in various colors to suit
          the furnitures of the room for which they are intended. The moat htfh* [onablc watch chain
          worn is a short fob chain, with a ball at the end. which inavbe plain, chased or set with
          Jewels. We did not know that they were called Queen Anne watch-chains, but that is
          probably the name by which they arc known to some fashion writers and to jewelers. Grena
          dines are BOperceded by canvas or etamine fabrics nowadays, but are still worn by a few
          conservative ladies. Great variety in form and color of upholstery, draperies and all the
          pieces of furniture in a room is per mitted by fashion at present. In fact, what is called
          by some writers the eloctric room that is. a room furnished with choice furniture
          representing various modern or medieval periods of art furnishings, and harmoniously
          combining several subdued colors with one prevailing tint or tone is considered the height
          of taste. But it re quires OHKA.T JUDGMENT in selecting the pieces of furniture, the cur
          tains, carpets, decorations and ornaments of such a room. There is danger of mak ing it
          look like a furniture dealer's collec tion. The rage for decorated china, or delft, is on
          the wane, but when plain white is used it is selected of the finest ware, and is sometimes
          made decorative in the fluting or waving of the pieces in dotting, scallop hie. denting or
          flagreting the edges, the handles and borders of the cups, dishes, sauces, plates and side
          pieces. The most exquisite and fanciful shapes of antique, niediseval and modern pottery
          are chosen, all done in white. Then, if color is de manded on the table, it is supplied by
          flow ers, all one color if possible, by fancy col ored glass and open drawn work lines in
          the tablecloth, showing the bright color of the fine flannel cloth placed under the white
          one. Sometime a long mat of velvet or plush of the color of the flowers and glass on the
          table is placed down the center of the same, and on this are placed the eperjoie, a
          central glass etna for tlowers and lruit, and the little bisque. j tiuures holding btekete
          t;dl of bon-bons, candied fruits and motto ptpan, the fancy glass tlowor receivers and
          flower-! and choice pieces of silver. For a toilet set. decorated china, or. lu'tter
          still, fancy cut glass, is the correct thing. I'Koi'i.i: Mo !ma».im; that the fMMR men and
          women of Xew York society are stiil and formal in their Manners would have been somewhat
          sur prised at the ciowdot vonng peoplt who gathered before 1 O*deek feeteVdajf after noon
          to play bidminton in a «|iucr little Fourth avenue buildinK- Nobody wn> v,.|,. (>us for an
          instant, and chaff seeniol to Ik> tbeorderof the hour. Over in one corner sat four maids
          as upricht as dolls and as solemn as East [pitta fakirs. The? conversed in low tones and
          seemed utterly oblivious to the tfume. .So d;d mo>t of the others for that matter, and it
          didn't take a voiy shrewd observer to dis cover that bandminton. as played" in New York,
          consists ni conversation*; to a very large extent. Interspersed with a few cur sor, bits
          of hit and mi-play with the racquets. There were no chaperones at all at this RUM, and it
          amounted to a merry tort ot frolic Cor two hours bj the middle of the day. li wm MMuing to
          Hstento the talk, tor the Kugiish accent, which bj affeoted so laboriously by some of the
          so ciety people, m picked an and dropped pieci-«'ly as fancy dictated by the gor geously
          attired people who made badmin ton an excuse lor Betting without being oppressed by the
          pres ence of chaperone dnenneti Hut just let me show \ou how superior bolles are to beans
          when it comes to sightliness at play. Tbe biggest swell of the dandies arrived an hour
          before time. He was a small man w ith prominent teeth, rather a pallid face, and a pah* ol
          shadowy side whiskers. He penneed up to the door of the liiuisy frame structure, and
          nodded carelessly to a stolid Englishman who stood by the d«»or with a straw in his mouth
          and his hands in his pm fcete. "Good mawnin". Fowbes." said the new- Coiiier. screwing* a
          elng inlO one of bb) weak ejea, and glaring hard at t lie at tendant; "is any one beahf
          ••Not yet. sir, "'^liuilK' attendant, respect fully. "Aw." muttered the fOUg man compla en
          ly; "1 am the tirst one then."' Baring arrived at this deep and logical conclusion, after
          AX KI.AnonATH COl*Rhe east a and transparent smile at Forbes, and drifted through the
          doorway into the barn-like structure. Here he cast a critical view at a net which extended
          across the Moor, went to one of a series of small lockers, and took therefrom a rac quet.
          Then he ascended the small >uir way to the gallery, where there were I few dressing-
          rooms, and presently emerged in all the glory ol white llaunel knickerbock- ers and shirt,
          with long red stockings, a blue nnd white silk Norfolk jacket, and a blue worsted Tarn
          O'Shanter cap perched artfully upon his rather peculiar-looking head. Around one of his
          slim wrists there was a broad leather band clasped with four buckles a scheme by which
          champion badminton aud tennis players strengthen wrists that have been strained by
          overplay. The single glass now hung over his breast. He danced about fora moment to limber
          up his legs, and then, stepping out in the iu closure across which the net was placed, he
          slipped oflE his little cube into which was inserted a rim of feathers and tossed it in
          the air. When it came diving downward, with bullet-like directness he caught it deftly on
          the end of bin racquet and sent it into the air agate. building and imparted the Still 1
          km look to it that a conservators midsummer. Occasionally the .in., car bell could be
          heard but nobody luliruiutl into the Badminton club. The only signs <»f life were supplied by the nimble young
swell who danced carelessly about in the
sunshine, batting the feathered toy up to
ward the roof. With the rich colors of his
costume and his nimbleness he might have
been tnistaden by a buloonist peering from
above for a huge tropical bird of some cay
but gawky sort disporting itself grotesquely
in the sun.
THE SOLITARY
young; badminton player who was romping
so joyously was a howling swell of a very
high order. He didn't look like a man of
pint importance, but socially his position 1
is enviable. A man who at the age of j
twenty-eiirht can boast of membership in
the Summerset club, of Boston; the Savage
club, of London; the Jockey club of Paris,
and the Union. Knickerbocker and Union
League clubs, of New York: has a racing
■table of his own and spends SGO.OOO a
year without earning the reputation of
being a spendthrift or a fool, must neces
sarily amount to something in the woild of
society. lie seemed as happy as a clam at
high tide, batting away there skillfully,
when a brougham drove up to the door and
a young woman and her maid bustled in he
gave a yell of meeting that was quite un
dignified, and reminded one strongly of a
street Arab.
••Late again. Miss Agatha," he chirped,
happily. "Ton me soul it is quite heart
rending for a man of my conscientiousness
and t lustful nature to receive these disap
pointments every play-day."
''Indeed, you are a paragon,"' said the
jrirl. smiling brightly, and aoastaglsßf wraps
t" the maid. "It was the fault of mamma
Ibis morning. She was desperately blue
when she irot out of bed, and so she climbed
bark in again. Then she insisted upon my
rending to her until she felt more composed,
and there you are."
She had scarcely finished speaking when
there was a great chatter and bustle about,
and half a dozen people hurried in. Two
of the guls were in full tennis rig. and
when one of the men slipped off his long
ulster he revealed the fact that he. too. had
put on his play-day togs before suiting
from home.
WHAT STRUCK ME HARDEST.
However, was the fact that the belles
were so much more shapely and graceful
than the beaux. More than one bony fellow
had on what 1 believe actors call "Mats."
That is to Kay, their legs were artificially
enlarged and straightened by padding. No
till was jruilty of such deceit. But 1 don't
mind telling you just what girl; do in their
One when costuming for badminton or ten
nis. The fashion is to wear soft woolen
skirts retelling to the ankles, and presuma
bly with no petticoats underneath. The in
tention is to leave the legs clear for the ex
ercise—also distinctly outlined as part of
the mend symmetry that constitutes so
much of the pleasant sightliness of the
■port. Well, every player of good sense
puts on exactly as many flannel skirts as
will produce the desired bulk. No speota
toi can tell whether there be one or six lay
ers of the soft fabric; but anyhow he never
sees the protuberance of a knee-pan or the
sharpness of a shinboue. Clara Belle in
Cincinnati Enquirer.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047239/1886-10-13/ed-1/?sp=5&q=badminton&r=-0.095%2C0.513%2C0.706%2C0.599%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          PLAYING BADMINTON
          A TWO HOJRS FROLIC FOR NEW
          YORKS SOCIETY YOUNG FOLKS
          Arrlrnl of the UlcucstHwolI of tlio Dun
          silo Aflor nil ISlnbornte Cniirne of
          Thought Sixty Thtinsnnil u Ycnr nutl
          i llio ltesiilta Thormf
          People wlio lnmglno tlmt tlio young men
          and women of Now York society tiro still
          mul formal In tholr manners would have
          been somewhat surprised at tlio crowd of
          young pcoplo who met together ono
          nftornoon to play badminton In a queer
          little Fourth avenue building
          It didnt take a very shrowd obsorvcr
          to discover that badminton as played In
          Now York consists of conversation to a
          very largo extent Interspersed with n fow
          cursory bits of hit nnd rclsplay with tho
          racquets Tlicro wore no chnperones at
          nil at this gamo nnd it amounted to a
          merry sort of a frolic for two hours In tho
          middle of tho day It was amusing to
          listen to the talk for tho English accent
          which Is affected so laboriously by soino
          of tho aocloty people was picked up nnd
          dropped precisely as fancy dictated by tho
          gorgeously attired pooplo who made bad
          minton an excuse for meeting without
          being oppressed by tho presence of chnpur
          one duennas
          A DKEP AND LOCIICAL CONCLUSION
          Tlio biggest swel of tho dandlos arrived
          an hour before time Ho was a small man
          with prominent teeth rather n pallid face
          and a pair of shadowy sldo whiskers Ho
          pranced up to the door of tho flimsy frame
          structure and nodded carelessly to a stolid
          Englishman who stood by the door with n
          straw In his mouth and his hands in his
          pockets
          Good mnwnln Fowbes said tho now
          comcr screwing a slnglo glass Into ono of
          his weak eyes and glaring hard at the at
          tendant Is any ono heahf
          Not yet sir said tho attendant re
          spectfully
          Aw muttered tho young man otm
          plncently I am tho llrst ono thon Hav
          ing arrived at this deep nnd logical con
          clusion after an elaborate course of
          thought ho cost n ghostly and transparent
          sinllo at Forbes mid drifted through tho
          doorway Into the burn liko structure
          Hero he cast a critical view at a not which
          extended across the floor went to ono
          of a sorlos of small lockors and took
          therefrom a racquet Then he ascended
          the smidl stairway to a gallery vhoro
          there were a fow dressing rooms and pres
          ently emerged In all tho glory of whlto
          flannel knickerbockers and shirt with long
          red stockings a blue nnd whlto silk Nor
          folk Jacket nnd a blue worsted Tom
          OShantcr cap perched artfnlly upon his
          rather peculiar looking head I Around one
          of his slim wrists there was a broad leathor
          band clasped with four buckles a scheme
          by which champion badminton nnd tenuis
          players strengthen wrists that have been
          strained by overplay Tho single glass
          now hung over his breast Ho dnnccd
          about for a moment to limber up his legs
          and then stepping out into tho Inclosuro
          across which tho net was placed ho
          slipped off his silk jacket produced n llttlo
          cube into which was inserted a rim of
          feathers and tossed it in tho air When it
          came diving forward with bullet llko
          directness ho caught It deftly on the end
          of his racquot and scut it Into tho air
          again
          A HOWLINO SWELL OK IIIOII OllDCB
          Tho solitary young badminton player
          who was romping so joyously was a howl
          ing swell of a very high order Ho didnt
          look llko a man of great Importance but
          socially his position Is enviable A man
          who at tho agtuf 23 spends ftWOOO a year
          without earning the reputation of being a
          spendthrift or n fool must necessarily
          amount to something in the world of
          society Ho seemed as happy ns a clam at
          high tldo batting away there skillfully
          when a brougham drove up to tho door
          and a young woman nnd her maid bustled
          v in ho gave n yell of greeting that was quite
          undignified nnd reminded ono strongly of
          a street Arab
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>
          https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1890-03-09/ed-1/?sp=18&q=badminton&st=text&r=-0.462,-0.348,1.616,1.616,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>PLAYERS OF BADMINTON. JWO CLUBS WHER1- THE WRDS" ILV >VEB THE NETS. A DESCRIfTION Of
          THE GAJfE-IT- POPTJIiAltlTT AS A I.KNTl-V AMUSEMI \T >*a pkople wi llesown is The pame of
          badminton, "f nli games "t akill. is pcrhaps loast kti .wa by iho publle i.t large. It is
          ncarly as mueh a game "i egilitj and quick ncss as iciinis, and, altho igb the Mercite
          required is not Tlolent, thecnjoymenl experlenced i.y tbe playcrs in a cloaely oontested
          game la Jui kcen as m tho more wldely known -istor game. lat nn Indlfferenl player
          badminton i- much the r.etter form nt sp-'M. and iho women w o go io lor it are mdre
          entbuBlaatic iu it* supporl than the most eonfirmed playcra -.i tennia The liko it becauae
          it givea them an nppetite. and iu this it nevei f.ii!-*. Cocktalla ire i t. to I c com
          jiaicl with H- Sherry and bitters hecomes na aotbing, nnd ;i good dinnei preceded bj
          badniin tBadminton may be played either 'i the lawn or ladoors. ln Ita Indoor fonn it is.
          and is likely to renniin. Sew-York'a fashionable L??nten paatime aml n- auch ii certainly
          deservcs praise. 'Ih.' game aa now played i-- nol ..t greal i?? tlquity, oi il ll la,
          there ia no deflnlte reoord of the lni't, lt ia "I Anglo-Indlan origln, and baa been
          siii.o 1E. i u favorite with -.ngllab oJheera i" India. The form ol game played ln
          Sew-York ri..es not diffei materlallj fr..m thal played bj tho Aiiin.ilai'i'l Badminton
          Club In India. and the rulA* now adopted ure pructically tlie -ainc Tho BBaterlala for
          badminton aro differcnl iboee uaed for tei igb the gai mlghl appeai simil r n e net la
          from two feel to two feel si_ ii cl es in bre idth, ai I ln_t<
N-i.'i- sei upon tlu ng poles
nnd ia 1 ung al a distam c ol from Hve i"
j et to six fe 1 from tbe surfa. e oi Ihe court.
Inste i-l ol balls, sli ittlecocka, or bir la," oa they
nrc teehnlcally c lled, are used. Tlie racq cts
nr b it* with which l aboul are
rencrally ol a Lighter weighl and souiewli kl smaller
than the ordinory tennis i icque.,
tennla ruc<] et can be For in
door pl ig a i ird" wei ;1 i incc is
iiaed, bul oui or?, un ac. wind, i ce
weighliLg. an ounce and three-eeTered with rubber to prevenl uu urj from nio__t
urc, is I'
            .-fi-.
            Vl_vr>'</text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn97065075/1891-06-19/ed-1/?sp=1&q=badminton</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          A GAME FOR ALL SEASONS.
          It Is Called "liadiulnton" ud Cuuie From
          England.
          Badminton was invented, or origin
          ated, whichever you please, in England,
          but owes its present rules to the Ah
          medabad Badminton club of India,
          Which has practically revived the sport.
          It is a modification of lawn tennis, with
          some important differences, as will be
          seen further on, and has the advantage
          that it can be, and generally is, played
          in-doors. This make3 it both a suramet
          and winter game.
          Tho dimensions of the court must be
          decided in a great measure by the capa
          bilities of the room in which the game
          is played. Tho best size Is one twenty
          eight feet long by twenty feet broad.
          The courts should bo marked off by
          means of pegs and strings, or better,
          when possible, by white chalk lines oe
          the floor, and divided in the following
          way: At each end ol the ground are
          two courts, ten feet square, while the
          center is formed by a piece of neutral
          ground eight feet broad by twenty feet
          long. On each of these outer lines of
          the neutral ground and in the center
          are placed tho posts which support tho
          net The net, which is two feet to two
          feet six inches deep, is suspended at a
          height of six feet from the ground, and
          firmly held by guy ropes attached to
          posts.
          The racquets used in Badminton, to
          be easily and quickly Wielded, should
          be lighter than those used in lawn ten
          nis, and consequently smaller. A shut
          tlecock is used instead of a ball, and
          may be large or small, according to tho
          wish of the players.
          In its general line, Badminton is a
          game played in the same fashion as
          lawn tennis, with tho exception that
          from one to four persons may play on a
          side, and that tho shuttlecock must be
          returned on the volley. Tho shuttle
          cock is served and returned under tho
          same provisions, except that, of course,
          if the shuttlecock falls on the ground,
          it Is counted as a miss to the player
          missing it, and to his side. The servico
          shall be from the "service-corner," tho
          server and receiver each standing with
          both feet within their respective quad
          rants until the shuttlecock is struck.
          The divisions of the respective courts
          are only observed in the serve or first
          hit; after that, the partners may stand
          where they please, on their side of tha
          net The shuttlecock must be served
          in such a way that it falls clear over the
          net, without touching the net, ropes or
          posts, and falls inside the lines of the
          service-court If the net Is touched in
          service and tho shuttlecock falls over,
          the stroke is considered as a "let," and
          does not count as a fault against the
          person serving. In play, however, the
          touching of the net by the shuttlecock,
          when it falls over, is counted as good
          stroke. If the net is touched by the
          racquets of the players, or if they reach
          over the net with their racquets, tho
          stroke counts against them. Two faults
          puts "hand out" In all cases a shuttle
          Cock falling on any of the boundary
          lines Is regarded as a fault, as if it had
          fallen outside Of the boundary lines,
          both in service and play.
          Iifteen points constitute the game.
          In service no overhand stroke is allow
          ed. The shuttlecock is judged by where
          it strikes and not by where it lies after
          striking. In judging whether a player
          has reached over tho net, the umpire
          should bo careful to note if the shuttle
          cock Is struck before it has crossed the
          net and not by the racquet of the play
          or, which is naturally carried forward
          by the impetus of the stroke and which
          might arrive at a slight angle over the
          net, although the shuttlecock itself was
          struck on the correct side. If, however,
          the net is touched by the racquet the
          stroke counts against the player, wheth
          er the shuttlecock was struck on the
          right side of the net or not
          As will be seen from the description,
          Badminton requires agility and a quick
          eye, rather than great strength, and it
          will be found to be a game at which
          girls can play with pleasure and profit
          Golden Days.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045604/1891-05-31/ed-1/?sp=9&q=badminton&r=-0.203%2C0.019%2C1.221%2C1.036%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        IrHE NET AND RACKET.
badminton Has Not Driven
Tennis From Favor.
BOSSIP OF THE CHAMPIONS.
I y Mabel Cahill, the John L. Sullivan
•f the Xew York Club, and Other
i Great Flayers.
1
i jriw YORK. May 25.—[Special Corre
jpoodence.J—The tennis season of 1891 has
fairly begun, and from present appear
ances it will be the liveliest one that has
aver been known in this country. There
was a prospect earlier in the season that
badminton might supplant the older game
in favor, but every one concerned now
scouts the possibility of such a result. No
one, naturally, takes a keener interest in
the question than the makers of tennis
goods, and they report the largest advance
tale* on record. It is one of the not to be
forgotten consequences of the popularity
of lawn tennis that the manufacture and
nleof neta, rackets, lawn markers, shoes
and uniforms has become a great industry.
It is only a few years since all these goods
were imported from England, the home of
fee game; now they are practically all
Bade here, and th» business amounts to
something like $10,000,000 a year to the
trade. This is looking at the other side of
the sport, but the point of view is not an
unimportant one.
The clubs in and about New York are in
nnmfctr almost legion, and they are pre
paring busily for championship events,
mcticaliy the season begins with Decora
tion day, the month of fine weather before
that date being given np to practice play
ing. Of course, play begins earlier South.
The Washington City tournament for the
championship of the Southern states was
held in the middle of May. Tomorrow
the New York Tennis Club will hold its
spring games, and from now to the end of
the season in October there will be a
tournament every day—for not a summer
hotel of any size is without its tennis
courts, the smaJlest villages have their
clubs, and matches and return matches
t are shrewdly relied upon to keep up the
interest in the game.
Undoubtedly the success of tennis is
OLLIE CA MPBELL.
largely due to the fact that men and
women can play it together. For flirta
tion purposes it may not quite eoual the
sedate and sluggish game of croquet,
but for a judicious combination of
sport and opportunities for tete-a-tetes
its equal has never been invented.
Indeed, tennis is the ideal ladies' game.
As it requires agility rather than strength
to play tennis, there is no reason why
women should not play quite as well as
men, if it were not for the perpetual haudi
cap ot skirts. As it is, an active young
woman is about a match for a stout and
middle-aped man, with equal practice, and
some of the l>est women players can hold
their own with any but the very best men.
i his is a test not to be recommended,how
ever, as the practice of playing with one of
the other sex rather tends to break a man
up. as he is divided between his gallantry
and his desire to excel. Thus it may easily
happen that a man will show tip in better
form at the end of a season with compara
tively little practice with men than if he
had considerable careless playing with
women. Championship games are, of
course, always between players of the
•tne sex.
•Since Scars, of Boston, who was an ex
fi.>rdinary tennis player, met with a dis
cing accident, the honors of the game
Jwe rested with the Brooklyn players
Henry \V. Stocum, jr., son of General ll!
W. Slocum, the champion of iw>, and Oli
"Ollie" Campbell, the present
bolder ot the championship, both having
park in past years,
though Mr. Slocum is ;IOR a member of
P:. George's Club, of New York. There is
perhaps no place in the country where bet
ter provision is made for tennis playing on
large scale than at Prospect park, and
there are few days in spring or summer
when a considerable number of games are
lot going on there simultaneously.
The frequency of va ant lots in the resU
yace sections of Brooklyn rather favors
KINKY W. STOCFM. *R
information of small neighborhood clubs,
Asocial amusement rather than tine
**y the result.
Jill!! orlt Vf 3 the younc woman
f«g l f rather expected to win chief chain-
honors this summer. This is
Mabel K. Oahiil, of the Net York
lennis Club. Miss Cahill is an
woman ami won lame in the old
nir\ at tennis tournaments before com
lhl* Bhe is a vigorous, aihletic
younp woman, with merry, iaugh
yes, ana quick, vi« -rous movements.
It4mlv r^ Sen 10 ,^r woman's cham-
I P**nn P h 3 K Will not
withom
t n l her s:s!
amp i° nfhll> for <*oubks. Miss
VA probabiy play in double# wiU\
SIXTEEN PAGES.
Miw Ballantine, of the New York club.
Miss Robinson, of Staten Island,
Mrs Morgan, of Short Hill*. N. J.,
the Misses Kiting. Frazer and Temple, of
Westchester county, and Miss Colby, of
Orange, N. J., are among the famous play
ers who may contert for the honors with
Miss< ah:i! and the Roosevelt sisters. Of
course, there will be dark horses, too, who
at the last moment mav appear to wrest
the leadership away from the well-known
plavers. It is always more difficult to
predict women's piaying than men's.
They have more time for practice, they
are quite as numerous, if not more so. and
they are far less likely to enter champion
ship contests than men, even if quite pro
ficient. Thus local pride may almost at
any time force to the front some splendid
player before unheard of outside of her
county. It is the peculiarity of the plav
ers of both sexes that they are at their
best while quite young and do jiotlong
retain their supremacy.
Badminton came to the front last winter
as an indoors game, for which it was well
adapted by the smallness of the court re
quired. A tennis court is 78 feet by 27
wider than an ordinary city lot and nearly
as deep. The badminton court is only 44
feet by 20, and can be recommended for a
home game where spare is verv limited.
The net is shorter and higher. The short
service line is 6 feet 6 inches from the net.
The base line is 15 feet t> inches farther
back on either side. The net itself is 16
feet long and 5 feet high in the middle.
In the play a shuttlecock is used in
stead of the white ball used in ten
nis. This is made of rubber and
feathered to steady its (light. Ordinary
tennis rackets are used instead of the ola
faehioned "battledores." The game is, in
fact, a sort of cross between lawn tennis
and the older game, and is said to be the
invention of an English officer in India,
who found the climate too hot for ten
nis. Perhaps that is the reason why old
tennis players call badminton a lazy peo-
Sle's When such sturdy at hletes as
[amihon Cary and .Stanley Mortimer and
such clever tennis experts as Miss Annie
Webb, Miss Turnure, Miss Minturn and
Miss Elsie Mitchell play and enjoy thgame, however, it can safely he assumed
that, there is plenty of exercise in it.
The rules of badminton are so simple
that they can be summarized in a para
graph. There is no authoritative Ameri
can body like the National Tennis Associ
ation, but the English rules are used:
The sides toss for choiceof ends or service
before the first game of a match, and change
to the other sideof the netafter each game.
The single-handed and double-handed
game consists of fifteen ares. At "13 all,"
the side which first reaches thirteen has
the option of "setting^'five; at 14 all, of
setting three. In three-handed or four-
handed jrames the game consists of twenty
one aces. First set is at 19 all; second at
20 all. A fault made by a player whose
I side is in puts a baud out; if made by a
j player whose side is out it counts an afe to
i the in side. It is a fault if the service is
I "overhand"; if the rirs-t part of the path of
the shuttlecock is inclined downward ;if the
service falls into the wrong court; if the ser
vice falls short of the service line or outside
the bounding line; unless both the server's
teet are in his own court; if the shuttle
cock falls outside the bounds of the court;
if the shuttlecock does not pass between
the posts, or if it pass under or through
tiie net or touch anything except the bat
of the striker, or the top of the net if the
shuttlecock !>e hit twice intentionally by
tiie same player; if the shuttlecock be
struck before it crosses the striker's side of
i the net; if the striker touch the net or its
supports with his racket or otherwise,
i The player in the right-hand court com
mencea the game by serving to the plaver
in the adverse right-hand oourt; if tfiat
leaver return the shuttlecock, it must be
hit ack by the in side and then returned
by the out side till a fault is made by one
j side or the other. The game is continued
in this manner, count being chanced after
j each ace ;s made. The service lines nre
disregarded alter the serve is returned,
j Iho innings always begin with the player
j in the right-hand court, and serves arc
i made alternately from each court into the
one d. t.; iia.lv opposite. In two. three
and tour-handed games, the side begin
ning a game has only one hand in its nrst
innings if there are two a side, and only
two hands if there are three a side. Inatwo
h and el game only the ptrson served to may
take a serve; not so in a three or four
handed game. The service must not begin
till the opponent is ready, but any attempt
to return is taken to indicate readiness.
Any unforseen or accidental hindrance
may be given by a "let" bv the umpire on
appeal from either side "before the next
service commences or before the players
have changed sides at the end of a game.
A "let" cannot be claimed it" an attempt
I ha* been made to strike the shuttlecock
Pitiably the next winter there will be a
badminton association iu this country r or
the new game may he taken under the
l government of the tennis association.
Magistrate (severely^—Why 'id
drive through the crowded thu fhfarea
at the rate of t:!teen miles an htur? I>o
you tlunk that the streets belong o you?
Culprit (earnestly protesting >-B_it,yg(Ur
honor, 1 drm a beer wagon.
PLAN OF A BADMINTON OOt'P.T.
A GAME OF BADMINTON
Fightint for Ills Hi. t
New York Sun
THE SEATTLE POST-INTELLIGENCEE.
        
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1891-10-04/ed-1/?sp=8&q=badminton&st=text&r=0.149,0.525,0.162,0.274,0</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      Champion Badanlatoa Tennla Playara,
Th Badminton lawn tennla axpert yesterday mo
eeeded In capturing both of the sterling silver trophies
In th recently formed Inter-Club Tennis Association of
King county. The scoresi
Gentlemen' Single Flnt round: B, IV Booecek,
Knickerbocker Field Club, forfeited to A. 8. Mertam,
Badminton Tennis Club; Dr. W.N. Fraser. King County
Tennis Club, beat B. 8. Ueltcamp, Altlora" Tennis Club,
e 8, ft 0; E. L. Heltrarap, Altlora T. C, beat A. Fransl
ola, Knickerbocker Field: Club, 82, 84: C. E. Mao
Mabon, Badminton T. C, beat A. G. McGowan. King
County T. C, 84. 80; A. 8. Merlam, Badminton T.
C, beat Dr. B.O. Fraser, Kings County T. C, 03, 08,
78.
Second Round K. L. Ileltkatnp, Altlora T. 0, beat O.
E. MacMabon. Badminton, T. O. 76. 88: A. 8. Mer
lam, Badminton. T. C, beat Dr. B, 0, Fraxer, Kings
County T. C tt-4, 68. 7-6.
Final Round A. 8. Merlam, Badminton T. C, defeated
L. lleltkamp. Alt.ora T. C. 0-0. 7-6, 82.
Gentlemen' Double, First Round E. H. Payne and
H. E. McGowan, King County T. C. beat E. L. llelt
kamp and H. B. lleltkamp. ARortaT. C, 8-8, 6-3: A.
8. Merlam and C. E. MarMahon. Badminton T. C. beat
K.H.Lou and Harry Wall. Knickerbocker Field Club,
fl 01; Harry rranclola and William Boocock.
Knickerbocker Field Club, beat J. 8, Jones and John U.
Rollins, Altlora T. C..H-0. 68,81; Dr. R.O. Prater
and F. M, Pendrelgh. Kings County T. C beat Dr. V. A.
Griffiths and O. N. Hchmtdt, BadmlntonT. C, 8-2, 8-0.
Heeond Round E. M. Payne and II. E. McOowan.
Kings County T. C were beaten by A. S. Merlam and C,
R. MacMabon. Badminton T.C., O 2. 2-fl, 0-4: Harry
Pransclola and William Boocock, Knickerbocker Field
Club, were defeated by Dr. W. N. Fraser and F, M. Pen
drelgh, Kings County T. C, 8-8, rt-O.
Final Round Dr. Prater and F. M. Fendrelgb. King
County T. c., were beaten by A. 8. Merlam and c E.
MacMabon, Badmldton T. C 13-11. 810, 67, 0-1,
68.
      </text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-11-10/ed-1/?sp=45&q=Badminton&r=-0.373%2C0.508%2C1.469%2C1.246%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      GAME OF BADMINTON
I Copyright by James Elver son
ITTS^~ ADAITNTON was invented,' or orig
|J Ij inatcd, whichever you please, in
I !*•"*_ England, but owes its present rules
RtjlSSSfj to the Ahmedabad Badminton Club,
Mvlfilr" o f India, which has practically re
vived the sport. It is a modification
of lawn tennis, with some important differ
ences, as will be seen further on, and has the
advantage that it can be,- and generally is,
played indoors. This makes it both a sum
mer and winter game.
The dimensions of the court Imuit be de
cided in a grjfat measure by the j capabilities
of the room in, which the game lis played.
The best size ii one 28 feet long- by 20 feet
broad. The courts should be marked off by
means of pegs and strings, 'or better, when,
possible, by white chalk lines jon j the floor,
and divided in the following way: At each
end of the ground axe two courts. L jlO feet
square, while the centre is formed by a piece
of neutral ground 8 feet broad by 20 feet long.
On each of the outer lines of the neutral
I ground and in the centre are placed the posts
which support the net. .C-
The net, which is 2 feet to 2l2 l feet 6 inches
deep, is suspended at a height of 6 feet from
the ground, and firmly held by. guy ropes at
i tached to posts. ,y L
1 The racquets used in Badminton, to be easily
and quickly wielded, should be lighter than
those used in lawn tennis, and consequently
smaller. A shuttlecock is used instead of a
ball, and may be large or small, accorum" to
the 'wish of the players. .7 .1
In its general; line, Badminton is a game
played in the same fashion': as lawn tenni*,
with the exception that from one to four
persons may play on a side, and that the shut
tlecock must be returned on the volley. -_•
The shuttlecock is served and returned
under the same provisions, except that, of
i course if the shuttlecock falls on the ground,
it is counted as a miss to. the player missing
it and to his side." The service shall be from
the "service-corner," the server I and receiver
each standing with both feet within their
respective quadrants until the shuttlecock v
struck.
The divisions of the respective courts are
only observed in the serve or first hit; after
that the partners may 1 stand where they
please, on their side of the ¦net....
The shuttlecock must be served in Mich a
wav that it falls clear over the net. without
touching the net, ropes or posts, and falls in
ide the lines of the service court.
If the net is touched m service and the
shuttlecock falls over, the stroke is oonsid
i BOYS AND GIRLS MAGAZINE SECTION
At tltc first tfelfOi 'crawAe&6>r J fyr/ff£ Jttf/a /}&3&7ered 38 a "let," and does not count us a fault
against tbe person serving.
In play, however, the touching of the net
by the shuttlecock, when it falls over, is
counted as good stroke.
If the net is touched by the racquets of the
players, or if they reach over the ne£_ with
their racquets, the stroke counts against
them.
Two faultf puts "hand out." In all cases
a shuttlecock falling on any of the boundary
lines is regarded as a fault, as if it had fallen
outside of the boundary lines, both in service
and play.
Fifteen points constitute the game. In ser
vice no overhand stroke is allowed.
The shuttlecock is judged by where it strikes
and not by where it lies after striking.
In judging whether a player has reached
ever the net, the umpire should be careful to
note if the shuttlecock is struck before it
has crossed the net and not by the racquet of
the player, which is naturally carried forward
by the impetus of the stroke and which might
arrive at a slight angle over the net. although
the -shuttlecock itself was struck fairly on the
correct side.
If, however, the net is touched by the
racquet the stroke counts against the player,
whether the shuttlecock was struck on the
right side of the net or not.
As will be st%n from the description, Bad
minton requires agility and a quick eye, rather
than great strength, and it will be found to
be a game at which girls can play with pleas
ure and profit.
DIGNITY AMD IMPITDPNCe'
      </text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1909-05-23/ed-1/?sp=29&q=badminton&r=0.642%2C0.728%2C0.204%2C0.173%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      BADMINTON TENNIS CLUB
HOLDS FIRST DAY'S PLAY
SANTA MONICA, May 22.—The
newly formed Badminton Tennis club
held its Brit play today on the Third
street courts. The club is the offshoot
of the Badminton dub, which held
sway last season, and Includes some
of the best racquet wlelders of South
ern California.
Among thus,- who will bi seen on
id, i club (milts this season are Mrs.
i; i,. Warring, the Mlssea Archer,
Miss Ryan, Miss Marshall, Miss Rower,
lliss Nettleshlp and Mrs. Bruce.
      </text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1920-03-28/ed-1/?sp=23&q=badminton&st=text&r=0.288,0.592,0.496,0.496,0</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      Will Boom Badminton
j The Badminton Club, of New York,
an organization established in 1878,
I which has continuously since that time
I tried to foster and develop the game of
I badminton in this city, will hold 07;
I Saturday, March 27, an intercity tour?
nament with Caines Badminton Club.
I of Boston. There will be four matches
of men's singles, three women's sin-j
gles, two men's doubles, one women's
doubles and three mixed doubles
      </text>
      </result>

      <!-- TODO add links to 5 non-relevant passages -->
      


    </results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-daylight-saving</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038411/1918-03-16/ed-1/?sp=15&q=daylight+saving+time&st=text&r=0.165,0.416,0.335,0.569,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        PASS DAYLIGHT
SAVING BILL;
AWAITS WILSON
Clocks All Over Country Will
Be Turned Ahead
One Hour
Wusliington, Mar. 16—The House
of Representatives, by 252 to 40. yes
terday passed the Senate daylight
saving bill, under the terms of
which, when it receives the signa
ture of President Wilson, it'will be
required that all the clocks in the
United States be turned ahead one
hour at 2 a. m. 011 Sunday, March
31, and remain advanced one hour
until 2 a. m. on the last Sunday in
October.
Under the bill parsed by the
Senate the limit was, fixed as the
last Sunday in September. The
House amendment extending the
daylight saving one month was
adopted upon representations by-
Fuel Administrator Garfield that a
great amount of l'uel would be con
served thereby. It is expected that
the Senate will concur in the amend
ment to-morrow.
Five standard time zones for th
United States will be fixed by the
Government, according to the bill,
and it is made mandatory upon the
railroads to follow the standard
time.
By the passage of the bill, tho
United States joins with England,
France, Switzerland, Portugal and
the three Scandinavian countries in
adopting a method of economy and
efficiency first taken by Germany
during the early days of the war.
Millions of tons .of coal have been
saved in these countries, it was
stated to the House to-day by the
supporters of the measure, by the
simple means of turning the clock
ahead over a period of five or six
months a year.
England reports a saving of 12,-
000,000 tons up to date. Several
Representatives who espoused tha
bill admitted that when it was first
proposed they considered it silly.
But, they said, when they came to
examine its virtues they fell enthu
siastically behind it.
Provided the President signs it,
and there is little doubt that he will
do so quickly, the daylight-saving
bill will have the effect of turning
us all out of bed an hour earlier
than we have been accustomed-to
arise and of sending us back again
accordingly. The use of fuel at
night will be conserved by the clos
ing of establishments at 11 o'clock
which ordinarily do business until
12 o'clock. By the clock on the wall
it will still be 12 o'clock, but by
the moral conviction it. will be 11.
Officials of the Chamber of Com
merce and the Bourse, two of the
many local organisations which car
ried the light for the daylight-sav
ing bill into the very halls of Con
fess. were jubilant on receipt of
the news that the legislation was
so near. Ernest T. Trigg, president
of the Chamber of Commerce, said:
"This is very gratifying to us. By
a readjusting of working hours the
war industries will be speeded up
materially and more time for the
cultivation of war gardens will re
sult."
Emil P. Albrecht, president of the
Bourse, said:
"This legislation will enable work
ers to get better results out of their
daily efforts, as they will be in bet
ter tune for speeding up operations
in the early daylight hours of the
summer months. In such a large
manufacturing center as Philadel
phia the gain in efficiency in the
various war work lines will be tre
mendous. Only on Monday last the
directors of the Bourse urged upon
Congress for the second time within
two months the necessity for this
change."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1918-03-16/ed-1/?sp=1&q=act+change+changes+Clock+daylight+daylight-saving+HOURS+law+Saving+standard+time&r=0.086%2C0.334%2C0.744%2C0.631%2C0&st=text</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Nation Moves Clocks Up
One Hour Easter Sunday
Daylight Saving Bill Passes House by Big Ma
jority as War Measure?Some Opposition
from Farming Communities.
Clocks all over the oountry will
be set ahead one hour, beginning
March 31, under the so-called day
light-saving bill, pessed yesterday by
the House, 252 to 40.
Senator Calder, author of the
ure In the upp?r braftch iftf Congress,
said the House amendments would
be agreed to, so that a conference
would not be necessary.
Provisions of Bill.
The bill provides that at 2 o'clock
p. m. on the last Sunday In March
each year, clocks all over the country
which affect any operations of the
Federal government, or railroads,
i shall be set ahead one hour. At 2
j o'clock p. m., the last Sunday in Oc
j tober of each year, they are to be
i retarded one hour.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030431/1918-03-24/ed-1/?sp=58&q=daylight+saving+time&r=0.052%2C0.481%2C0.875%2C0.742%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      Daylight Saving Is Simplicity Itself
How Ben Franklin s Idea Conceived in 1784, Just Made Into Law Here, Will Affect
Folks After Easter and Save Millions to the Nation
10
By WM. ARCHIBALD FERGUSON,
Secretary of the National Daylight Sar
ins Association.
ON Ihc coming Apwl 1 more people
in the United Slates will probably
be April fool vietims than on any previ
ous or future April 1, for Congress lias
decreed that at 2 o'clock on the morning
of March 31 the hands of the clock shall
be turned forward one hour; in other
words, the United States will then begin
to live under the davlight saving plan,
and doubtless thousands will forget to
make the change.
Every individual who is wise Jind hates
to be fooled will before retiring on the
evening prior to Kaster Sunday, March
31, see to it that not onh his watch but
every clock in the bou.se is turned for
ward one hour. Otherwise on Sunday he
will find the Easter services half over be
fore he arrives at the church, and on
Monday morning, April 1, VMS, rising
an hour late, if he is a commuter he will
miss his morning train by an hour and
be greeted at the factory or office with
such remarks as "April fool!" "You day
light blacker! You forgot to turn your
watch ahead, eh 7'' and all day long he
will be the butt of many jokes.
May Wait Lone for Dinner.
If lie starts for home at the tame hour
as usual and has not during the day tele
phoned his wife to turn the clock ahead
be will have a long wail tor dinner. One
thing Is certain, hotvivcr. that before he
retires that night crry member of his
household will know that the daylight pav
ing plan is in effect and that the people
of the United States are living an hour
ahead of sun time.
The daylight sating idea U almost as
Id as the United States it-elf and our
country can rightly claim the credit for
all the many advantages which will act-rue
from it, not only in this country bat also
in those countries which anticipated the
United Slates in its adoption, for it was
Benjamin Pranklm who Iirst conceited
the idea.
On an early morning walk along the
Etreels of Imdou in 17.S4 the thought Iirst
came to him, and in passing if on to the
world at large he said:
''In a walk through the Strand and Tit et
ttrect one morning at 7 o'clock I ob.-Ttcd
then; was not one shop open, although
it had been davlight ami the sun up
above three hours, the inhabitants of
lxndon choo.-iug voluntarily to live by
candle light and sleei by sun-bine; and
yet often complaining :t little absurdly of
the dnty on candles and the high price
of tallow.''
Soon thereafter in the Jtwrnal Je
Faris he publL-hcd an article, later ap
pearing among his es-ays under the title
4An Economical Project," which further
elaborated the advantages of daylight sav
ing; namely, of "Turning the clock for
ward an hour" so that everybody would
live one hour longer by davlight and one
hour less by artificial light.
Beaten Repeatedly in Britain.
Tor many years in England in the
last century Sir William Willctt annually
introduced his davlight sating bill in Par
liament and annually the bill wa- de
feated amid laughter and ridicule.
In 1915 Germany tirst adopted the plan
to speed np the war production and io
benefit by the tremendous saving in fuel
consumption. France and England and
nil other European countries except Rus
sia soon alter followed her example.
Since its adoption in Europe, the.
United State.-, Canada and Mexico have
been out of harmony, so far as time was
concerned, with European countries, to
their loss not only in business, for the
stock exchanges of Ixindon and Paris un
der the new plan were closed before the
exchanges of New York and I tost on were
open, but also as regards the tremendous
savings pos-ible in light bills, which, it
is estimated, annually will run from V0,
000,000 to $50,000,000 in the United
Sfates alone.
The plan has been ardently advocated
in this country since May, Wlfi, by the
Merchants Association of this city, cham
bers of commerce of Boston, Rochester,
Philadelphia, Chicago and Pittsburg, the
United States Chamber of Commerce,
Washington, D. C, and the National Day
light Saving Association, of which Marcus
M. Marks, former Borough President of
Manhattan, is the president. Mr. Marks
has often been called the '"'father of day
light saving in this country."
To illustrate the effect of the. plan, let
us follow Jack Hurryup, a New York
commuter, through his first business day
under the new regime.
Mr. Hurryup is a habitual reader of
The Scn, and accordingly he knows he
should on the evening of March 30 turn
his watch and clocks ahrad one hour be
fore he retires at 9 o'clock. But on the
night of Easter Sunday he goes through
the house from the kitchen to the
roof and advances each clock one hour
and is surprised when he arritis iu his
bed chamber and looks at his watch to
lind that he is retiring at 10:1.1 instead
of i:15 his lirst shock from daylight
saving.
The alarm dock rings louder than
usual the next morning and he. jumps out
that several of his friends to whom he
telephones have not yet arrived at the
office, but are expected auy minntt.
At 1 o'clock, his usual hour, he hurries
to the restaurant for luncheon and finds
a slim crowd. Upon returning to the of
fice all is running smoothly and at quar
ter of 5 he closes his desk to catch the
5:15. As he passes through the gate at
the Grand Central he sees the same fa
miliar crowd starting on their nightly
journey home.
Ed, Kill and Dick are on hand for the
nightly game of poker, .lack and his
friend Ed were the losers in the game,
for they spent most of their time joking
Bill and Dick for being April fools aud
having missed the train in the morning.
Alighting from the commuters' special
in the country, he is happily pleased to
note that it has not vet begun to grow
BENJAMIN FRANKLIN
jr FROM THE ENGRAVING OF THE DUPLESSIS' PORTRAIT OF 1778
Noted American philosopher is the father of daylight saving.
of bed at C:.'J0, leans out of the window
and noles that the sun is ju-t ri-ing, and
then realizes that he is really getting up
one hour earlier by the sun, although the
alarm went off at the usual hour.
He rushes through his bath and his
breakfast and runs for the train. When
he arrives at the station he is surprised to
find many of his pals missing. The train
pulls in and he runs to his customary scat
in the smoker: the table and the cards
are there, but only one plajcr besides
himself. He greets Ed .(ones, who
boarded the train at the station, above
with:
"Good April fool joke on Bill and
Dick! Guess they forgot to turn their
watches ahead last night. We'll have
some sport with them to-morrow."
Mr. Hurryup piles into the subway
aud is astonished to lind a seat at the
Grand Central, his second shock from
the daylight saving. "Guess a lot of peo
ple are fooled by this daylight saving
this morning," he mutters to himself.
He arrives at the office, looks at the
clock to see whether he has consumed the
usual time on his journey down town and
is surprised to find that he is arriving
at 8:1.1, the exact time at which he took
the tram at his station. Shock No. 3.
No oflice boy in sight. He rings for his
stenographer and she greets him with a
hearty "Good morning He tells her
to get the porter immediately and turn
that oflice clock ahead one hour.
He finds no mail on his desk and con
cludes that the letter carrier is also one of
the daylight saving April fo;Is.
The morning runs on as usual except
dark and that the sun is still shining
brightly at 0 o'clock. "We fooled ton to
day. Old Sol, and will keep fooling you
until November 1," he says to himself.
Arriving at the house he goes to the
cellar, and finding that he need not turn
on the lights he gels out the lawn mower
and bis garden tools.
"This daylight sating is all right," he
calls up fo Mary; ''don't hurry to get on
the dinner. I am going to mow the lawn
and wotk in the garden until sundown."
After an hour's work about the grounds
.lack comes in to dinner and he anil Mary
agree that daylight saving is the greatest
boon ever conferred upon New York com
muters. The chief benefits of the plan, as
proved by the experience of England,
France and other European countries
where it has been in force, may be gen
erally summarized under three heads:
Eirst General health of all people
benefited by reason of an added hour of
daylight in the late afternoon, which has
been and will be u-ed for outdoor recre
ation and exercise.
Second Increased production of food
stuffs through the stimulating cultivation
of home gardening.
Third Money saved in lighting bills:
each householder will burn artificial light
one hour less each day, provided, of
course, he continues his usual habits of
retiring at night.
The report of the summertime commit
tee appointed by the British Parliament
in September, 1!1G, to inquire into the
social and economic results of the sum
mertime act shows that the extra hour of
dat light was generally ucd for the pur-po-e
of outdoor recreation and pursuit's,
and, in particular, for the cultivation of
home gardening.
The athletic dubs reported that the
cricketers, bowlers, golfers and tennii
players took full advantage of the extra
hour of light, and swimming pools and
playgrounds were utilized to full capac
ity. Iu view of the national agitation last
year, which is being renewed now, for
the cultivation of home gardens to in
crease the production of food the inaugu
ration of the daylight saving plan iu this
country will undoubtedly very greatly
stimulate home gardening, particularly in
the neighborhood of the great cities. In
New York city alone there are 1,000.000
daily commuters. Should only one-half
of them use the extra hour of daylight
which the plan will give in cultivating
home gardens there will bo 3,000,000 extra
hours utilized weekly in gardening and
during the seven summer months in which
the plan is in operation 2,000,000 days of
extra work and time will be spent by
these 500,000 commuters in the cultiva
tion of gardens.
What It Means in Potatoes.
It has been estimated that if the av
erage commuter wpre to work a plot of
land only 20x-10 feet, which would le
about I-50lh of an acre, and planted it all
to potatoes, on the basis of 300 bushels
per acre each commuter would he able
to rai-e from four to live bushels of pota
toes; on this basis half of the commuters
of New York city would add to the potato
crop during 191S approximately 2,500,
0011 bushels.
The saving in lighting bills ami in fuel
u.-ed for producing electricity and gas
wdl be tremendous. Public Service En
gineer Robert L. Bruuct of Providence,
If. I., has carefully estimated this saving
and fixed the amount during the period of
live mouths, which the plan originally
contemplated, at $-10,000,000, and tiie
amount of coal sated at 1,000,000 tons.
This sating will he unitersal as every
hou-eholder will u-e one hour les- of aili
licial light daily under the new plan.
Other additional benefits will be the re
duction of traffic accidents due to Ici-cncd
tran-poriation of pa'.sengers under arti
ficial light, reduction of the danger of eye
strain on account of the lessened amount
of reading and work done under artiticial
light and more lime for open air military
drilling.
The davlight sating hill as signed by
President Wilson on March 19 provides
lhat the plan shall go into effect at 2
o'clock antemeridian time on Sunday
morning, March 31, at which time clocks
and watches, probably upon a signal
flashed from the United States Naval
Observatory at Washington will be
turned ahead one hour. Comparatively
very few individuals, unless by design,
will be conscious w hen the change is
made. "This hour was selected by reason
of the fact that at 2 o'clock in the morn
ing the number of railroad trains actually
en route is smallest,
Nobody Will Be Inconvenienced.
Nobody will be seriously inconte
ilienced, unless on Easter Sunday morn
ing or on the night previous individuals
forget to turn their clocks and watches
forward an hour, as the result of which
omission they may find at some time dur
ing that daj- that they arc one hour be
hind the rest of the country.
The remarkable thing about the effect
of the movement is that practically no
class of business will be injured; the only
exception is the open air moving picture
exhibitors-, who under the new plan will
be. unable on account of the sun's setting
an hour later to begin their performance
as early as they have been accustomed in
previous years, which may result in a
loss of patronage. The ordinary business
man, as far as bis business is concerned,
will not be affected in the slightest, ex
cept that he will be more often tempted
this summer to go to the baseball game
which will begin at -1:30 o'clock instead
of 3:30 and to run down more often to
the beaches for a dip before dinner.
Everybody under the new regime will
continue his old habits rising, working,
dining and retiring at the same hours;
we will still live by the clocks and give
the laugh to the cob.
      </text>
      </result>


      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064305/1918-03-28/ed-1/?sp=1&q=daylight+saving+time&r=-0.01%2C0.086%2C0.933%2C0.792%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      Daylight Saving is
Law Of Land.
r- Don't make any dates for 2:30
t, Sunday morning, March 31, be.
st cause there ain't gonna be no
ill sich animal. In fact, there will
le be no 2 o'clock. At 60 seconds
le after 1:59 it will not be 2 o'clock
but 3 o'clock. Similarly, if you
contemplate any sort of engage
ment, business or social, for 1:30
Sunday morning Oct. 27, you
g had better make plain which
v "1:30" you mean, because there
n is going to be two of 'em on that
y day. Exactly 60 seconds after
1:59 a. m. Sunday morning, Oct.
27, it will not be 2 o'olook, but
1 o'clock again.
That is what President Wils'i
n did Tuesday, March 19, when he
n affixed his signature to the day
light bill which had already been
passed by congress. As a result,
the Muniversally accepted plaint
d that life is growing more com
plex every day, has another sup
porting argument.
However there is going to be
very little confusion, after all.
Just remember to do this, and
you'll be all right:
Before you go to bed on the
night of Saturday, March 30, set
every watch, alarm clock, grand.
father's clock, cuckoo clock or
other timepiece in the entire
house, one hour ahead.' This is
going be done in every house
hold in the entire United States.
On the morning of Sunday, March
31 when you awake, the change
will have been accomplished.
</text>
      </result>


      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=2&q=daylight+saving</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      If you do so understand the daylight-saving-
law, and there are many
who are puzzled, do .not worry. Just
before going- to bed tonight advance
your clock one hour that Is. make
It an hour fast and then forget It
Go about 'your business as usual.
You will notice no difference or
change, except that, the sun will rise
later and will set later. The even
ings will be an hour longer.
Under the Jaw. all of the clocks of
the nation must be. advanced one 'hour
at 2 o'clock' tomorrow morning-.
There, is. no need' of staying, up until
2 o'clock, however: you can turn the
clock up Just aa well before, going to
bed.
Here's a lip.
If perchance you are prone to stay
out late Saturday night be sure and
tell wlfey the time' when you come
in. before the clocks are turned up,
otherwise you will be an hour worse
off. 'for official time will akip from
2 to 3 o'clock in an Instant tomorrow
morning-.
      </text>
      </result>


      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=3&q=daylight+saving&r=0.538%2C0.687%2C0.611%2C0.518%2C0&st=text</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      CANADA TO SAVE DAYLIGHT.
ties. lire like lulled states' tu Me
I'aaaed un.
OTTAWA. Oat., March 10 The
Canadian Havitght saving nin. t-
rsspondlng to the measure which be
Comas effestlve In the t'nlied tttatea
lo-morrow, will i i-.i.- be paaaed
in about a fortnight When the
Senate resumes in April ft. daylight
ssvlng will be the first Important
legislation before It
      </text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-03-31/ed-1/?sp=8&q=daylight+saving&st=text&r=0.286,0.601,0.162,0.274,0</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      Text of Daylight Saving Law
An act to save daylight and to provide, standard time for the United
Be it enacted by the Senate and
United' States of America m. Congress -ossemDiea, mat, ior ine.pur-.
pose of establishing the, standard time of the United States, the ter
ritory of continental Umted States shall be divided .into five zones in
the manner hereinafter provided. The standard time of the. first zone
shall be based on the mean 'astronomical time of the second, .zone, on
the.ninetieth degree; that of the third zone, on the one hundred and
fifthdegree; that, of thefourth zone on .the one hundred and twentieth
degree, ard that of the fifth zone, which shall include only Alaska, on
the" one hundred and fiftieth' degree. That the limits of "each zone shall
K AofmaA hv an nrtloi- nf thp Interstate Commerce Commission, having..
regard for the convenience f commerce and the existing. jucc.tion J
points and division point 'of common .carriers engaged in commerce-J
between the several States' and. with foreign nations, ana sucn oruer
'may be modified, from time to time. r
o Tht within the resnective zones created under the" auth
ority hereof Ihe standard time of the
oi all common earners rengagca in- commerce ikhvbm -mo kici
States or between a State and any of the Territories of the United
State, or'bftween a State or thtfrTerritory of Alaska and any of the,
insular possessions ottlie United States orany lereim countrytflrf
all statutes; orders, rules, and regulations relating, io the time,of,-per-;
formance of any act by anyof ficer or .department of the United States,
whether in the legislative, executive, or, judicial branches of the Gov
ernment, or relating to the tinre within which any rights shall accrue
or determine, or within which any act shall or shall not be performed
by-any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, it shall
he Understood and intended that the time shall be the United States
standard, time of the zone within which the act is toibe performed.
Sec? 3. ThaJ; "at two" o'clock antemeridian of the last Sunday inj
JIarch of .each year.jhe standard time oi cacn zone snail De advanced
one hour, and at two o'clock antemeridian of the last Sunday in
October in each year the standard time of each zone shall, by the re
tarding of one hour,-be returned to the mean astronomical time of the
degree of longitude governing said zone, so that between the last Sun
day in March at two o'clock antemeridian and the last Sunday in Octo
ber at two o'clock' antemeridian in each year the standard time in each
zone shall be one hour in advance of the mean astronomical time of the
degree of longitude governing each zone, respectively.
Sec. 4. That the standard time of the first zone shall be known
and designated as United States. Eastern Time: that 6f the second zone
shall be known and Designated as United States Standard Central
Time; that of the.third zone shall be Known and designated as United'
States Standard Mountain Time; that of the fourth zone shall be
known and designated as United States Standard Pacific Time; and
that of the fifth, zone shall be known and designated as United States
Alaska Time
Sec; 5. That, all Acts and parts of Acts in conflict herewith are
hereby, repealed.
Approved March 19, 1918.
      </text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87057262/1918-04-01/ed-1/?sp=5&q=daylight+saving&st=text&r=0.301,0.367,0.335,0.569,0</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      What became of that hour between
2 a. m. and 3 a. m. Easter morning?
Where did those sixty minutes go
which were abolished from the face of
thd earth?
Thirty-six hundred seconds extermi
nated when the clocks of America
were turned ahead.
Keoktik observed the daylight sav
ing law Sunday morning by turning
the clocks ahead one hour. And every
The earth Is approximately 24,000
miles around. It makes a full turn in
twenty-four hours, or travels at the.
rate of say one thousand miles per
hour. We poor mortals, clinging to
the earth as best we can are being
whirled around at this excessive rate
of speed. We are going some. Yet
Sunday morning at 2 o'clock, when the
clocks were changed, we made an ex
tra jump of a thousand miles in our
mad race. Did you notice the change?
The miser has $200,000 out at inter
est at six per cent. His income from
this is $1.37 every hour of the day.
Sunday morning he made an extra
$1.37 when the clocks were changed.
But when the clock is changed iback in
October, he will lose an equal amount.
The sick man was to be given a pill
every half hour. The nurse had been
instructed to be very careful in fol
lowing out the instructions. Some
body changed the clock and she got all
muddled up as to whether to give the
dying, man two extra pills. It was a
case of life and death. The nurse
fainted and the poor sick man got no
pills all night long. When the nurse
regained consciousness, her patient
had recovered and was out working in
his war garden.
The early worm had become tired
of dodging the early bird every morn
ing, so the worm made his trips over
the top an hour earlier each day. But
the bird observed the new daylight
savings law and met the worm half
way as usual.
A certain man came home at 2
o'clock. Before retiring he changed'
the mantle clock. When it struck the
hour of two he shoved it ahead anoth
er hour and it struck three. Then he
went to bed. In the morning his wife
accused him of coming home at five.
No argument was allowed. She heard
t0
the^cloek strike five. Oh, what's thejold
The clock In West Keokuk, in
Lincoln school belfrey. was hanging
six bells -at seven o'clock Sunday
morning, one of the few sla-ckers in
Keokuk. The hands have since been
changed and the clock is now running
on war time with the others.
      </text>
      </result>

      <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87057262/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=7&q=daylight+saving&st=text&r=0.292,0.003,0.482,0.862,0</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
      TURN THE CLOCK
AHEAD TONIGHT
Just Do Thle When You Go to Bed
Tonight and Then Forget to
Worry About Ttiat Ad
ditional Hour.
GIVES YOU MORE TIME
If You Play Golf Just Think of the
Extra Daylight You'll Have to
Chase Over the
Green.
JUST DO THIS AND BE CONTENT.
8et all clocks and timepieces ahead
One hour Just before retiring Saturday
night.
Those who are awake at 2 a. m.,
Sunday, may wait until that hour to
set their timepieces ahead one hour.
Ahead—-forward—one hour. Under
stand this and do it, and having done
it, be content, nor worry any more
about it.
This simple Instruction, obeyed so
thoroughly that every timepiece in
the oountry la thus changed one hour
ahead, will carry out the law and pre
vent any confusion whatever. Every
phase of life will move ahead with the
cloaks—trains, street cars, business,
religious services—everything. The 9
o'clock trains Sunday morning will
leave at 9 o'clock by the clock. The 7
o'clock atreet cars will run at 7 o'clock
by the clock—everything will be Juet I
as it Is now, by the clock. And the riotic
clock will be the only thing to rely on
as
It Is now. Just what!his
the clock says, after It has been turned
ahead one hour, that will be the time,
and the time for everything, Just as It
is now. There will be no change in
anything except the clocks and
watches, and no one need pay any at
tention to the fact that they have been
moved one hour ahead.
Complete plans for the daylight sav
ing system, which' goes into effect to
morrow have been announced by fed
eral officials and the nation's workers
are ready to push the hands of the
•clock one hour ahead to assist Uncle
Sam In hig fight for liberty.
Every city in the country, every
town and village, everything is in
readiness for the new system, a sys
tem that will save the nation thou
sands of tons of coal daily as well as
assisting the working man, the shop
girl and the laboring clasa as well as
the busy office man.
What this plan means to the nation
can be described in a few words. In
the first place It means the conserva
tion of the fuel supply. Secondly,-it
gives the average man more time to
devote to gardening, which In turn
means a "bigger supply of food for the
nation and, thirdly, it means a more
healthy nation.
The work of the masses will be done
In daylight, where, heretofore, it was
done In the dark a certain number of
hours a day.
Favored by All.
Since the plan was first spoken of
it has attracted the attention of some
of the biggest men in the country.
Efficiency experts have studied the
plans and in very instance have re
turned a favorable report on their
study.
The action has been favored by
President Wilson for the past several
months. Garfield and Hoover have
been ardent supporters of the plan.
There has never been an argument
against the system and every learned
man in the country is of the J.rsllef that
the plan will greatly aid the nation's
savings.
The daylight saving plan will give
the following daily advantages:
One hour or more for outdoor rec
reation. Recreation is a national as
set, an immense force for health and
moral well-being.
Working mothers and fathers obtain
an extra hour for outdoor play with
their children, both summer and win
ter.
One hour less for bad lights in tene
ments.
Lessened eyestrain for workers and
school children due to the use of artifi
cial light.
Smaller risk of accident in indus
trial establishments, because there
jwill he a light hour instead of a dark
one at the end of the working day at
,tlie time of greatest fati-gue and most
{frequent accidents.
Lessened risk of accidents due to
I transportation and traffic conditions,
because the afternoon rush will fall in
iduylight Instead of darkness,
Working girls will be on the way
home in the daylight instead of in the
!dark in winter.
Our last hour of sleep will be sound
ier and more 'beneficial than it is un
der present conditions, because there
will be less light.
General efficiency will, of course, be
•increased by any improvement in the
(health morals and social welfare of
tiie workers and others.
Morning Coolness.
I In summer a cool hour In the morn
jing is substituted for a hot one In
I the afternoon.
I In winter a light hour at the end of
the day is substituted for a dark one.
This is especially valuable com^g as
it does at the time of greatest fatigue,
and is peculiarly valuable in some in
dustries where aocurate eyesight is
essential.
Efficiency is lowest in the later aft
ernoon, the time when- accidents are
roost frequent.
There will be the greatest of all sav
ings—that of hnman materials, as
pointed out above.
Immediate saving in form of reduc
tion of expense for light and heat.
Ultimate saving in the conservation
QPHE DAILY GATE CITY^
of coal and other sources of light and
heat
Possilble reduction in the cost of liv^
ing of those who like to work in their
gardens, utilizing the extra outdoor
hour for this purpose.
A memorandum containing the fol
lowing important reasons tor the uni
versal adoption of the daylight saving
plan, looking at the matter from the
standpoint of war needs, was sent to
the house committee in February:
The training of the national forces
will be expedited, and the practice of
home guards and similar organiza
tions, the members of which have oth
er regular occupations, will be great
ly facilitated.
The production in all
I
plant3
Are Asked to Cover up Bargains If
It is Necessary to Dis
play Posters for Liberty
Bond Campaign.
A
large assortment of posters ad
vertising the third Liberty loan has
been sent to all township chairmen,
by County Chairman Dunlap, for use
in stores and windows everywhere.
The supply for Keokuk will be dis
tributed, probably by boy scouts,
throughout the business district and
it is hoped that merchants will give
them a very prominent position in
their windows, as the way to help can
the kaiser.
Some of these posters are works ot
the highest art, and some arevnot so
artistic. Some are in black and white
and some are in colors. All of them
are attractive and have a lot of force
of appeal in them.
"These posters were not designee!
to harmonize with the color scheme of
the milinery or the hardware in the
store windows," said Chairmfen
windows, even if they do hide some
mighty good bargains in spring styles
jor some goods formerly eight dollars
and now down to ninety-eight cents.
Raising three billion dollars to win
the war Is not exactly a matter of do
ing things conveniently, you know."
Tax Slackers.
St. Paul Pioneer Press: Collectors
-fniSrternal
revfnue.alln0Unce th^
,'^Wr
GATE
which
ore making materials for war use, in
creased, and the conditions of work
for their employes would be improved.
      </text>
      </result>



    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
